[Music]
Good evening and good day everybody and
welcome to the ask Abhijit show. We are
doing episode 319 today. I'm going to
take questions on all topics today from
the super chat mainly and if possible
from the regular chat as well. So let us
see before we get into the questions,
let's see who all is there on the live
chat. I can see Pratap Dana, Namaste. At
Timsat, hello. Nagaranda Shenoy from
Hyderabad, Anin
Animesh Bharatiya, Ram Ram.
Alvin Rodriguez who says is could this
be the beginning of World War III? Not
yet, not quite. Rajat Duhan, Ram Ram.
Putin 444, Pratap Dana, Sentinels by
Manisha Kardoso, Namaste. Nagaranda
Shenoy, Study V Study Vlogs, Random
Skull, Saw Me from Jaipur Sal Saslast
okay.
I user chat, it's been a while, Namaste,
good to have you. Good to have you back.
Sunil Civilian Wizard, Ayush Singh,
Pierre Vital
Pierre Vital, okay.
Vishnu Mohanan,
Vishnu Mohanan, Yan Kumar Bhujel, Trupti
Patel, Namaste. Khushboo Art, Namaskar.
Suhas
Reddy from Mangal, Namaste Ji.
Manhattan, Ritik Pawar, Shri Hari Arjun,
Rajat Duhan once again.
Manhattan all over again, Sentinels by
Sona Sandhu Ji.
Uh
Who else do we have? Himanshu
Rajpurohit, Mclovin69
says will China attack India? No, not
yet, not quite, not yet. Dhanush, Suhas
Reddy, Priyanshu Poli, She Trump, hello.
Priyanka Jawaliya is here from Gurgaon,
good to have you, ma'am. Namaste.
Humanity survives is here from from from
New York, hello.
Shivaprasad Civilian Wizard, Suraj Sagar
Himanshu,
Om Bekarika, hello.
Ritik Buddy Buddy X4W,
Vishnu Mohanan once again, Shashank
Kaushik, good evening. King Ritwik from
Bhubaneswar, good to have you, King
Ritwik from Bhubaneswar.
Manik Das, New Year, a happy New Year,
yes. Um
Sunil from Hunasigi, hello.
Shri Hari Arjun once again, Chaitanya
Chaitan Aradhya
Shatabdeesh
from Norway, hello. Nagaranda Shenoy
says what's happening in Venezuela? So
much has happened in Venezuela and it's
still well kind of events in motion.
Komal list and everyone else, okay.
Won't be able to greet everybody
individually, but let's get going with
the questions. Have I ever been to
Gurgaon? I was just a couple of like two
three days ago in Gurgaon. Yes, I was
there.
Um yeah, the the pollution, good God,
what's happening right now? Oof.
Geopolitical Dubai is here from Indore.
Akshat Dako Giri Ak
is from here here from Pune.
Khushboo Art, Khushboo Kumar
Sharad Sobhadra
Himanshu Rajpurohit is here from
Chennai, okay. Let's get going with some
questions, what do we have?
Shatab Shatabdeesh says more we read
Buddha more evident it is
as no self path of supreme consciousness
is Advait
and so are rituals. Wonder if Dr.
Ambedkar really missed this. I don't
know um
about Dr. Ambedkar and
what he has said about Buddhism, so I I
can't comment on that. I can't possibly
comment on that.
I haven't studied Dr. Ambedkar's life,
career, writings, any of that, so I am
absolutely no authority on Dr. Ambedkar,
that's why I refrain from commenting
about
him.
Um
When it comes to Buddhism, look, it's
part of an much older tradition, right?
We understand that.
Um it is
in Buddhism they say that, you know,
that you had lots of Buddhas before the
Buddha, before Gautam Siddhartha Gautam,
and there'll be more in the future.
That's okay, but the only Buddha we are
aware of
is Gautam Buddha, right? From the hard
evidence that we have, we are aware of
Gautam Buddha. And the tradition is that
they there were many Buddhas before him.
Uh but we don't have evidence of those.
So from what we see, Buddhism
what we call Buddhism today, the the
Buddha philosophy which is part of the
Dharmic umbrella
it emerged with the with the life and
career of Gautam Buddha. And obviously
that's it's a continuation of older
traditions that
way predate Buddhism. So you're going to
have these elements, significant
elements and borrowings from older
tradition.
So there's no surprise in that.
Okay, Died in Plane Crash says a
question from Prashant Barty, does
Putin have two secret sons? Well, if
they are secret, how will I know about
them? So I can't answer the question,
come on.
I mean, do you guys imagine that I know
about secrets that the whole world
doesn't know about? How is that
possible?
Yeah, so I am not aware of any secret
sons of
Shri Putin Ji, I'm not.
Black Star Clips says you've achieved
before how to you've explained before
how to achieve goals. Can you briefly
explain how to create systems to achieve
those goals? Look, creating systems is
it's
you can't explain in a couple of
minutes. The point is a system
it has an input and an output. It has a
trigger and it has an action and it has
a desired outcome.
So let's say you want to create a system
that gives you an efficient
start of day routine. So what's the
input? You opening your eyes is the
input when you wake up in the morning.
So immediately you need to have a system
as to what to do.
Essentially a routine, it's like a
ritual.
Right?
Um and you can have systems for for all
kinds of things. If you are if you are a
programmer, you can have systems for the
best which encodes the best practices
for programming. So I can't explain in
brief, it's not possible to explain
something like this in brief. A system
is you could consider it to be a routine
or a ritual or something that is
triggered by specific things and so on.
But systems is what gets you towards the
goals.
It is not having a goal isn't enough.
How are you going to achieve your goals?
Yeah, it's not achieved through
discipline and hard work and blah blah.
You need discipline, you need hard work,
but more than hard work you need smart
work. And smart work happens through
systems. You need the right goals and
you need the right systems for achieving
them day in and day out. And achieving a
a goal is an incremental process. You
have to break it down into bits, into
bytes, as small a bite as possible and
just keep on doing that, keep the eye on
the ball. You want to score a century in
cricket? You have to take it one ball at
a time. That's how it is. So even when
you're batting for example, you need to
have a system. You can't focus fiercely
throughout your batting innings, right?
The moment the ball is the bowler is
running towards you, you start
intensifying your focus. When the bowler
is is doing his, you know, gathering up,
that's when you focus fiercely and you
look only at the ball. Then you play the
ball and then you can allow your focus
to wander or relax
while the bowler goes back to his
bowling mark and then you start the
process again. So everything is a
system. You see, that's that's the
thing. But I can't explain in two
minutes, that's not possible.
Bhaskar Bandit says happy Gregorian New
Year. Well, same to you and same to
everybody else. Been watching you for
the past three years, you put a huge
impact on my life and millions like me.
Wishing you good health, support,
looking forward to all of us raising
standards together. Jai Bharat
absolutely, Jai Bharat everybody. Jai
and I I wish you all
the greatest of success and happiness in
this Gregorian year and and in the years
ahead. Thank you very much for the very
nice kind words you have said here. Um
means a lot.
And yeah, let's let's get keep going,
right? All right, Bhaskar Bandit Ji,
thank you very much.
And Bhaskar Bandit says after
Venezuela's success successful regime
change operation, seems Iran will be
next. A pro-US Iran regime will
challenge Russia plus China in West
Asia. How could Bharat navigate through
this? Future of Chabahar IMEC. Okay.
Now that we are talking about Venezuela,
you know, first of all,
isn't what happened in Venezuela really
fishy?
I mean,
you would have seen possibly, those of
you who are interested in this matter,
um, the clips that came out on social
media,
right? Of the American helicopters of
hovering over Caracas, the capital city,
and and firing whatever rockets or
whatever and explosions and so on. Do
you see a single instance in these video
clips
of somebody firing back at the at the
helicopters
from the ground?
Do you see any air defense activity?
There is a zero air defense activity.
Venezuela has reasonably capable air
defenses. They have Sukhois, they have
whatnot.
Nothing was activated.
Yeah?
So, it looks like it's it's pretty
clear, actually. It doesn't look like
it's pretty clear
that this was an inside job.
There was some kind of backroom deal
that happened.
The deal would have been probably
probably with key
individuals
in the Venezuelan government of Maduro
and with key individuals in the
Venezuelan Venezuelan military.
And the deal would have been
that we're going to come in, we're going
to take out Maduro, we're going to move
him to the US.
You guys will stay quiet. You guys will
not shoot back at the helicopters. You
will allow us to take him.
Then, you can continue ruling the
country
as long as you give us the oil, and we
will give you whatever you need
personally,
you and your families. We'll make you
super rich.
We'll give you privileges, but you've
got to sell out your country to us now.
So, that's been the deal.
It's kind of like Ashraf Ghani in
reverse. Ashraf Ghani 2021, the fall of
Afghanistan.
It wasn't really the fall of
Afghanistan. It was the US handing over
power to the Taliban.
And as part of that, Ashraf Ghani and
his government, they had to disappear.
So, when the Taliban made its move on
Kabul, did you see any resistance from
the Afghan armed forces?
Absolutely nothing.
The Afghan armed forces disappeared.
They dissolved into thin thin air.
And Ashraf Ghani also vanished.
So, this is Ashraf Ghani in reverse,
kind of.
Now, the question that Bhaskar Bandit is
asking after the successful regime
change operation in Venezuela,
uh, it seems Iran will be next. Well,
that is a possibility.
Yeah? The US is,
putting
all the place all the pieces on the
chessboard in the right places, right?
Step by step. So, the first thing, the
easy thing is Venezuela.
Do a deal with the Venezuelan, uh,
um,
socialist party and key people in the
military, you get Maduro, you give a win
to the American people, you get the oil,
you send a couple of
Globemasters to London to take away the
300 tons of Venezuelan gold in the in
the Bank of London.
You steal that,
and things are good.
All right?
So, Venezuela is done. Now, all other
little nations in in Latin America that
are pro-Venezuela, they will be really
frightened, and they will behave.
If they don't, deal with them, too.
No need, because you just blockade them
or whatever. There's no real resources
in the other nations. So, you're done
with the Western Hemisphere. The Monroe
Doctrine is implemented. The Trump
corollary corollary is also implemented.
Um, and then,
what are the other pieces that remain
that need to be fixed? Obviously,
there's a Ukraine war going on. You can
put it on ice right now. Let it go on.
It's a frozen conflict. Yeah? Uh, then
you have Taiwan. Well, China dares not
take Taiwan.
Yeah?
Uh, it all it does is saber-rattling
right now. It dares not take Taiwan.
It's not powerful enough, even though
Taiwan is right in its backyard. It
can't.
Then there is Iran then there is the,
uh,
question of Yemen, which is pro-Iran.
So, it makes sense to go for Iran next.
And that's what Israel desperately
wants. I mean, that's a big big big
demand of Israel to deal with Iran.
So, it's possible that Iran could be
next.
Now, you see,
the Americans took Venezuela. Did the
Russians do a thing?
Could the Chinese do a thing? Neither
Russia nor China have anything like the
power projection capabilities of the US.
Venezuela was a sitting duck.
It could have been done in a much more
bloody way, but they did it in the
easiest possible way. Kudos, America.
That's how you do it.
Now, if the US makes a move on Iran,
can Russia or China intervene?
I would say no.
I'd say no.
And I would say Iran has made a major
major mistake by not becoming a nuclear
weapons power by now.
Huge mistake.
Yeah?
So, it possibly could be Iran next.
When? We'll see about that.
If there is a pro-US regime in Iran,
well, if if the regime of the mullahs is
ousted, the current Islamic government
of Iran, then you will have some form of
pro-US government. Maybe the son of the
Shah of Iran will return
and be placed as a puppet Shah or
something, who will obviously
do everything the US tells him to do.
So, it becomes a pro-US government. So,
for India, to the west, we have
West Pakistan, the temporary nation,
which is pro pro-US and anti-India. And
beyond West Pakistan, further further
west, you have Iran now, which is a
pro-US government, which means it's
anti-India. It's a
bad scenario for India.
It's a really bad scenario for India.
Um, and it's bad for Russia and and and
and China as well.
So, what does Bharat do? What's the
future of Chabahar? If you have a regime
change in Iran, Chabahar is finished.
Forget about Chabahar. IMEC, India
Middle East Europe trade corridor, well,
that may continue if the Americans allow
it.
If the Americans find it beneficial for
them, it could continue. Otherwise, that
also disappears.
Most likely, it will disappear.
Or maybe it will be made to happen in
some other way. We'll see.
Chabahar, you can say it's finished.
Okay? Chabahar will be finished if this
happens. So, that That's where we are.
Died in plane crash says, "Your
prediction of Ukraine partitioned along
the Dnieper River, east it belongs to
Russia, west rump and the rest of the
rump rump Ukraine, is exactly the same
as John Mearsheimer. John Mearsheimer My
Shimer. Is this a coincidence? Also,
please watch his
podcast with Tucker Carlson if you find
time for it."
Uh, my prediction that Ukraine will be
partitioned, it's the same as the
prediction of John Mearsheimer. Is this
a coincidence?
Look, when you think logically, when
seven people think logically, if they
have logical minds, they will all come
to the same conclusions.
If they are,
well, reasonably intelligent, I would
say.
So, that's not a coincidence. If you ask
783 people
to solve
a differential equation, if they know
mathematics, they will all come with the
same solution, right?
That's Is that a coincidence? It's not.
It's just logic.
So, I don't think it's a it's some kind
of coincidence.
It's just that that is the most likely
outcome based on the logic of strategy.
Yeah? That's what's going to happen. I'm
telling you. I don't know I don't know
what John Mearsheimer has said.
John Mearsheimer had said that you that
Venezuela the Americans won't be able to
take it.
Well, that prediction, if it's a
prediction, has fallen flat.
So, you see, making predictions is a
pretty it's a super risky thing to do.
It's a risky thing.
Ideally, you should not make
predictions. You should make forecasts
after proper thinking, and a forecast
should always have a probability
attached to it.
So, this So, scenario A, scenario B,
scenario C. If you have seen my
geostrategy episodes, I usually give
three or four scenarios, each with a
probability attached to them,
right? To it.
That's how you do it. I mean, that is a
more rigorous way of doing things and
unlike saying, "You know what? I predict
this predict so-and-so thing will happen
in the future."
Uh, I am not in the business of making
predictions. Anyway, uh,
I'll
his podcast with Tucker Carlson. I'll
I'll possibly if if I can find the time,
I'll look into it. Thank you for the
recommendation.
Uh, Died in Plane Crash,
Died in Plane Crash, super sticker.
Thank you very much, sir. Thank you.
Parth Nand says, "Different variations
of
Yeah, let's not discuss this matter. I
not a big fan of this this nonsense, so
no.
Bhaskar Bandit says, "What's the angle
of Somaliland? Israel
has recognized it as a sovereign nation.
Can it be linked indirectly to
Iran-related dynamics in the region,
Iran's support to Houthi rebels just
across from Somaliland itself?"
Yesterday, I gave a detailed analysis
about Somaliland, the entire history of
Somaliland
and why it is geographically important.
Let's Let's run through it briefly.
Once again, okay? I will not explain the
history today, because that will again
take 20 minutes, and we're going to go
through a lot of questions today, uh, as
many as possible. So, let's look at the
map.
So, what is Somaliland? So, let us ask
Google. I know where it is, but just for
the sake of illustrating it, Somaliland.
So, it's going to zoom in here.
So, this region
is Somaliland, okay?
This region, and the capital city is
Hargeisa,
this one here.
And as you can see, this
de facto nation, which is now recognized
by Israel,
this de facto nation, it sits at the
mouth,
essentially
which it it overlooks three choke point,
which is the Strait of Bab al-Mandab,
which connects the Red Sea to the Gulf
of Aden.
And this is a vital geographic
geographic choke point because it
connects the Indian Ocean
to the Red Sea, which has another choke
point here, which is
the Suez Canal.
The Suez is a choke point, Gibraltar is
a choke point over here, this this here
is a choke point.
Then Suez
is a major choke point, Suez Canal.
Then you have the Strait of Bab
al-Mandab, which is a major choke point,
then there's an energy choke point here,
which is the Strait of Hormuz. And then
you have another choke point here, which
is Malacca. And that's vitally important
for China, but more than Malacca, it is
Hormuz and Bab al-Mandab that feed into
Malacca.
So, India, see, we in India talk about,
you know, we will choke off
this choke point. We'll block the Strait
of Malacca. Wonderful, our navy can do
it and we can blockade China. Fantastic,
India. You know how the Americans think?
They think that we will blockade
Bab al-Mandab and we will blockade
Hormuz.
They don't even think of Malacca. They
don't have to think of Malacca.
And that's that's how the Americans
think. So, if you essentially have
Djibouti in your pocket,
and if you have Eritrea, which is this
nation here, in your pocket, and then if
you have Somaliland in your in your
pocket,
then all you have to do is to find a way
to solve the Yemen issue.
If you can create a separate nation of
South Yemen,
which is in your pocket, then this
entire place can be blockaded on demand.
Essentially, this choke point, Bab
al-Mandab.
So, makes sense for the West to do it,
makes sense for Israel to now recognize
Somaliland.
And if Israel does it, maybe the US will
follow suit, and if the US follows suit,
then
all major nations, all the American
vassals will recognize Somaliland. And
then things fall into into place.
So, is this related to Iran-related
dynamics? Well, you see, Yemen,
the major
power in Yemen is the Ansar Allah
faction, which is also known as the
Houthis. They are pro-Iran and they are
anti-Israel, and they have
missiles that can reach Israel.
And they have missiles that they've been
firing at other countries like the UAE,
etc.
And they have been
actually, they have at times
successfully blockaded the Strait of Bab
al-Mandab.
So,
if you can solve these problems, solve
solve the Yemen situation by creating
South Yemen, which is not pro-Iran,
along with Somaliland, Djibouti, and
Eritrea, then the problem is solved.
Right?
So, if that is done,
then probably it will be easier for you
to make a move on Iran itself.
So, you know, like I said, Venezuela has
fallen, the Americans have taken over
Venezuela, Caracas. Um they've done a
regime change effectively over there.
Um now they could probably start working
on this issue of the Bab al-Mandab
Strait and the Houthis.
Then they could probably perhaps make a
move on Tehran itself.
And if Iran falls, then it's it's major
problems for Russia and for China
because Iran is a major ally for both
nations. It would be a big big big
setback for Russia and China. So,
everything is interconnected,
interrelated, and it's all part of the
dynamics that you are referring to.
Monish Sabrinath, pranam.
Pranam Monish ji. Thank you very much.
Monish Sabrinath says, "In recent times,
social media has shown
a growing trend of hatred toward men,
which even my female friends support. As
someone who has never harmed any women,
these labels make me question the
purpose of my life."
Okay.
See, this misandry, this hatred towards
men, it's it it's root cause is
feminism.
Feminism was a very valid and necessary
movement in the United States. It
emerged in the United States in the 18th
and 19th centuries. Okay? Women were
very brutally oppressed.
They do not have any rights, no right to
property, no right to, you know, no
voting rights.
Essentially, women were second-class,
third-class, invisible citizens. They
they had no rights. And that's why it
was very important for the women of the
US to emancipate themselves and free
themselves from this oppression. That's
why this movement called feminism
was necessary, and it emerged
eventually. And eventually women got the
rights that the men have, but then the
movement was hijacked by leftists, by
Marxists. And then it turned into
something entirely different. It became
a movement to oppress men essentially,
to subjugate men into relegate men to
second-class citizen status. Um
essentially, that's what it was. And
today, if you look at the US, it's a
gynocentric society. It's a
female-dominated society. Men are
second-class kind of citizens, you know?
That's how it is.
And the US exports its culture
worldwide. So, it exports feminism
worldwide. Now, you have all these
sociology departments in India where you
have feminist professors who will
do their best to to brainwash young
girls into into believing that there is
a oppressive patriarchy that has been
oppressing women.
It's tied to Hinduism in India. Men are
evil.
Women have been oppressed for thousands
of years, and women have to break the
shackles of this oppression.
And all your social media platforms,
which are owned by the United States,
will amplify these narratives.
And that's why even innocent,
well-meaning people will start believing
this propaganda
that men are evil, men are patriarchal,
oppressive, misogynistic,
etc., and women have to resist men.
Women have to break free of men. All men
are evil. There are
feminist women even have this hatred or
or this this dislike for their male
offspring.
And they try to feminize them.
And that's where all this trans and
transgender transgender stuff comes
from.
You see?
So, women in the US want to become men.
And they want to turn women into
They want to turn men into women.
Women want to masculinize themselves and
they want to feminize men. That's the
deal in the US, and this nonsense is
being spread across the world, and it's
it has over time taken root in India as
well. Even 20 years ago, 25 years ago,
this was taking root in India. In
various departments, you have these
short-haired female professors who would
teach this nonsense.
And that's why it's
you will see this now part of Indian
Indian
OTT platform culture, you know, you
know, um
all that stuff. Even high-ranking
politicians now push this thing. I say,
from my perspective, everybody should
have the same rights, men as well as
women, but no one should be positioned
as higher or lower.
And
one gender cannot be
demonized in this way.
Yeah?
So, that's what's happening.
But if this makes you question the
purpose of life, you have to introspect.
Um
it should not make you question the
purpose of life.
If you have female friends who regard
you as an oppressor and blah blah blah,
I think you need better friends.
Yeah?
So, um I'm not sure why it makes you
question the purpose of life. It's
It's obviously a problem in society.
It's a problem in society. It's an issue
in society.
And the solution is to fix the education
system, like I keep saying like a broken
record. I've been saying that for years.
But obviously, um maybe it's politically
convenient to to
to promote
not women's equality, but women's
predominance over men,
you know?
Uh so, it is what it is.
That's that's what's going on.
Bhaskar Bandit says, "What's on your
What is your analysis on the most
impactful geopolitical events we can
expect to see in 2026?" Well,
analysis is done about something that
happened in the past or the present
situation.
Asking me to analyze what's going to
happen in the future is asking me to
make predictions. I don't make
predictions. I'm not I'm not in the
business of making predictions. I can
make forecasts, but that will require
careful thinking and
plotting out everything on on the map
and so on.
So, I'm not going to make forecasts at
this point in time. I'm not going to
make predictions. Uh what can we expect
to see? What kind of trends could we see
uh in 2026? You can expect more pressure
on India
from the West, from the United States.
You can see more alignment, further
alignment between the US
and Pakistan and US allies in the region
with Pakistan.
The US allies in West Asia,
all of them.
Yeah.
All of them will align further with all
of them. Yes, full support, sir.
Who What else will we see?
There could be a US move on Iran
possibly. What's the probability? I'll
have to calculate that. I don't have a
probability right now for you.
Um
Will Taiwan Taiwan What's Taiwan? Will
Will China make a move on Taiwan?
Well,
I would say it's unlikely. Maybe I'm
I'll be wrong, but I think it will be
unlikely.
The US
is is
you know
The United States, its relative power
has been declining over time.
The US is now working on fixing fixing
that very rapidly.
Um so I'm not sure if the Chinese will
be able to make a move on Taiwan. Will
the Ukraine war end? I think
I'm hopeful it will end up by the end of
2026, but who knows. So these are some
of the things that could happen. West
Asia could be a problem. There could be
possibly operation Sindhu 2.0, possibly.
Uh what's the likelihood? I'll have to
see. So yeah, that's that's the kind of
stuff we can expect. Um more nations
will recognize Somaliland. There'll be
more
Well, Africa, you know how it is.
So that will continue.
And have I missed something? Yeah, these
are the trends I can think of as of now.
The dollar will get stronger.
Bhaskar Bandit says, "Me and my friend
have been living in Russia for 7 years.
We met you in JD Summit 2023. Okay.
Well, okay.
Uh with promising Bharat Russia
relations, we wish to enter in port
export. Things Russia can buy from
Bharat. Given your experience of world
plus life, any guidance would be
appreciated."
Well,
guidance here on this platform about
import export, what we can export from
India that will be desirable in Russia
and and
which will have a demand in Russia.
Well, that's um
I'll have to think about it.
Uh Russia is obviously a more prosperous
society than India. So they can afford
to buy things that are more luxurious
compared to what the average Indian can
buy. So what kind of
things can India export that will be
um
that will be in demand in Russia.
Um
Obviously, um
the climate in Russia is different. So
the kind of textiles we wear here will
only work for a few months in Russia in
the summertime.
Um I
I I'll have to think about this, you
know. Um
What about industry? Heavy industry,
etc.
You know, one thing you could do is
manufacture keyboards in India.
I'm not kidding. Manufacture
high-quality keyboards in India.
Does Russia manufacture keyboards? I
think it's unlikely. Let me quickly see.
Okay, I mean
I'm just
doing this in real time.
Does Russia manufacture keyboards? Let's
see.
Keyboards.
Does Russia manufacture keyboards?
Russia does not have currently have a
significant domestic keyboard
manufacturing industry.
No commercial keyboards were being
manufactured within the country in 2022.
Does India manufacture keyboards?
Let's see.
India manufactures keyboards
uh made in India, etc.
Okay, so the thing is, look,
there'll be very few companies in India
that manufacture high-quality keyboards.
This is just one example I'm throwing
out.
Set up a company that manufactures
high-quality, world-class keyboards in
India. You don't need very high
technology for that.
You just need good, robust, high-quality
keyboards that are a pleasure to type on
and which will last.
Manufacture these in India.
Export to Russia. Also also sell in
India.
And that's one example.
And obviously, there's a lot of stuff in
India that is, you know, more
aligned with tradition, etc. You know,
like um
clothing, textiles,
um furniture
maybe sandalwood stuff, maybe
uh
bags, carry bags and purses and whatnot.
That the I think
the the the opportunities and I ideas
are endless.
Um
So this I can one can think of plenty of
things that Russia can buy from Bharat.
The keyboard is a great idea, Indian
keyboards with no inbuilt
backdoors or whatever that the West can
exploit. Maybe that'll be something. I'm
sure there's there's a lot of ideas like
that that one can think of. But
yeah, this is a ideal in offline
discussion, not not an online
discussion.
Okay. All the best. All the best, sir.
All the best to Bhaskar Bandit. Do well.
Okay, Monish Sabarinath says, "What
message will you give to the great
future great leader of Bharat
if the future great leader of Bharat is
watching you now?"
What message will I give if the future
great leader of Bharat is watching you
now? Okay.
Always prioritize hard power. Forget
about this nonsense of soft power and
morality and all that. Power is immoral.
Always prioritize hard power. Hard power
trumps all of the forms of power. Once
you have the hard power, then you can
talk about soft power. Soft power works
only if you have if you have hard power.
Uh that's the first thing.
That's the first thing. And secondly,
technology trumps everything.
Without technology, there is no power.
If you want to be number one, you have
to be number one in technology.
That's number two. And what else?
Reform education.
Okay.
Dyed in plane crash, Mr. Prigozhin says,
"Why was USSR obsessed with submarines,
especially titanium ones?"
Oh well, you've been doing some reading,
have you?
What was it? Alpha class? Lira class?
1970s. Okay. So the question is, why was
the USSR obsessed with subs, especially
titanium ones? Even the US did not build
any titanium subs titanium submarines.
European and Typhoon Typhoon class subs,
why no one talks about Chinese subs?
Well, there are plenty of people who
talk about Chinese subs subs. Maybe
nobody in India talks about it. So let's
do one thing. Let me start talking about
Chinese subs. Then in a couple of weeks,
everybody in India will start talking
about it. And they'll they'll be
positioned as experts.
That's what typically happens. Anyway,
let's talk about the titanium
submarines of the USSR.
If I recall correctly, they were called
the Lira class. Lira class or Alpha
class. Maybe the name was
interchangeable. 1970s, maybe '71, '72,
somewhere around that time. The hull was
made of titanium and it had a very
specialized nuclear reactor.
Lead-bismuth cooled nuclear reactor.
Was it lead-bismuth? Was it
mercury-bismuth?
Um We we'll look it up in a in a moment.
It was a small submarine.
It was made as small as was possible
because the nuclear reactor could be
could be miniaturized because of this
novel cooling method. It was not cooled
by seawater. It was cooled by this with
this mixture of lead and bismuth or
mercury and bismuth.
Yeah? And it had a small crew. So let's
Google let's Google this quickly, okay?
Maybe we'll look at the Wikipedia
article. Uh
Lira class subs submarine.
Okay, Alpha class. Okay. Alpha class. Uh
yeah, nuclear power. These were
interceptor submarines, right?
Interceptors. A unique design. Bismuth
liquid Lead-bismuth, yeah. It was
lead-bismuth liquid cool liquid metal
cooled reactor as a power source.
Which greatly reduced the size of the
reactor, etc. Reducing the overall size,
allowing for very high speeds.
Must be around 40 knots or something.
How many knots? What The speed would
have been around 40 knots. K N O T S,
knots. 40 knots.
Okay, for in excess of 40 knots. Yes, it
was Which year was it? '71 to '90s. Yes.
So that's the deal. Lira Okay, it's also
called Project Lira.
Project 705 Lira, but it's called the
Alpha class.
Uh it means liar, the musical
instrument. Yes.
Uh and
it used titanium
for its hull. So titanium is is is is
harder than than steel,
but it's like half the weight roughly of
steel. Maybe less, maybe more, but it's
like significantly lighter than steel.
So you can have a much lighter
submarine, a submarine that can dive
much further, maybe 2,000 ft. Yeah? Or
more.
And the revolutionary design of the
nuclear reactor can en- ensure that it
can be significantly miniaturized. So
overall, the entire thing is much
smaller, way smaller than a regular
submarine.
So that's
what this Alpha class Lira class
uh set of submarines was.
And the USSR pioneered this.
Uh these were made of titanium.
Why was the USSR obsessed with subs?
Because submarines are way more deadly
than your goddamn aircraft carriers.
Please understand this.
I have been saying this for so long, but
people like, "No, no, aircraft carriers
Zindabad."
In India, we are still stuck in this
20th century mindset. The The Russians,
the Soviets
in the 1970s knew the future. That's why
they were obsessed with subs. Subs are
invisible. They are stealthy. They are
deadly.
Submarines are the most dangerous
type of naval asset any nation can have.
A submarine that's submerged, if it is
stealthy enough, it can wipe out an
entire aircraft carrier.
If you can
imbue it with sufficient stealth.
Okay? That's why submarines
are what India needs to invest in.
Anyhow, this The Soviets did this. Uh
the Americans did not build any titanium
subs. Why is that? Because titanium has
these unique properties. So when you are
welding titanium, when you're soldering
not soldering welding it together, if
you apply the wrong amount wrong kind of
heat to if you if the heat is too much
or whatever, then the titanium becomes
brittle.
Just a small mistake will make the
titanium very brittle and then when the
sub sub dives it may crack. The hull may
crack.
So, you have to be really really careful
while welding these hulls together.
And the Americans decided that you know
it's not worth the risk.
So, the Americans did not titanium subs.
The Soviets did a few and then I think
they also uh gave up on the project. And
then they used the same design with
steel, which meant that the sub would be
way heavier, but it still worked really
well.
So, that was the deal with these uh
Alpha or Lira class submarines. It was
an interesting experiment. I I don't
think anyone's uh making any any
titanium hull submarines today. But some
people have experimented with
experimented with fiberglass with
tragic results.
Uh now the Typhoon class I don't
remember the the Typhoon class. Let's
quickly look it up. What exactly was the
Typhoon class submarine?
Okay, let's see.
Typhoon
class submarine.
Okay. So, once again a okay, this is the
Akula Akula class.
Project 941 Akula. Yeah, what's what's
my opinion? I'm sure that it was good.
It was see see submarine development is
an iterative process. So, this was a
retired class of sub b b b b b b b b b b
Mhm. It was
it was built from '76 to '89. Service in
service from '81 to 2023.
Um
How many did we have? We had six were
completed.
Ballistic missile submarine.
And operators I'm sure history needs
etc. Typhoon class. Yeah, so okay.
Yeah, so that's the Typhoon class. See,
submarine development is an iterative
process. Iterative process. You develop
one class of submarines then you improve
upon it. So, each new submarine that you
build or new class of submarine, let's
say one submarine class will have five
or six submarines.
So, then and each of these submarines
will be somewhat different from each
other. So, then you do that and you
learn the lessons
from this design. And then you create a
new class of submarines which will
incorporate all the lessons you've
learned. And this this new class of
submarines will be iteratively better.
Maybe 10 20% better than the previous
class.
Then again in 10 years you do another
class of submarines. That'll again be
20% better. That's how you over the
years iteratively improve your submarine
designs. That's how it goes. That's how
it goes with fighter planes. That's how
it goes with most development.
Um and that's what the Chinese have also
been doing.
The original initial Chinese submarines
were very loud, very noisy, and very
inefficient. But now the Chinese
submarines are getting better over time
and they also have nuclear propulsion
submarines.
They're getting better over time.
So, yeah.
Died in plane crash says, are you
excited for Dhurandhar 2? Yes, I shall
watch it. I generally have this rule
that I don't watch Hindi movies, but I
broke that rule for Dhurandhar 1. It was
a pretty good movie. I liked it. And I
look forward to watching the second one
which comes out what? March? April?
Sometime this year. So, yeah.
I look forward to watching it.
UMXG lol haha says, is Namak a Persian
word or Sanskrit word?
As far as I know it's a Persian origin
word. It is not Arabic in origin.
It is Persian in origin. It means salt,
obviously.
Monish Sabarinath says,
Why do people demonize men for not
expressing feelings and link it with
oppressing women? This is all part of
this feminist nonsense propaganda and
all. Men and women are different.
Okay, it's just biological and
differences are biological, the
differences are psychological, the
differences are behavioral, and so on.
It is it's a fact. And this this
dichotomy is seen not just in humans,
but in all kinds of other species.
Uh so, if men are different from women,
why do they have to be demonized for
that? I don't get it. And if people do
that, why do you pay attention and why
do you bother with it? Why do you care?
Be yourself.
Just be yourself.
Uh what is this theories of this this
stoicism or whatever it is.
To hell with what people think and what
people say. You be you, you do you, and
you live your life and be happy.
Right?
That's what it is. I mean if you watch
all the 19
'80s and 1990s uh
action movies, that's your typical male
protagonist.
Stoic, doesn't express feelings, and get
gets the job done. That's your typical
competent man, isn't it?
So,
so don't I would say suggest
don't get hurt
when people demonize men or or
stereotype men or say that men should
not be men men should not men'splain
men's spread whatever. Why do you get
hurt?
Why are you feeling hurt?
Laugh it off. To hell with them. You be
you, that's it.
Don't let other people's opinions
make a difference in your life. Ignore.
Monish Sabarinath says, how did Vladimir
Putin take control of the Russian army
as he came by the route of politics? How
do politicians take control of army
without force?
Look, there is a system in every nation.
In the USSR there was a system. After
the USSR broke up, you had Russia.
And Russia had a system. In India we
have a system.
And for a functioning society and for
the benefit and for the safety and
security of the nation, everybody has to
follow the rules and the processes of
the system. Everyone understands that.
So, the people who are inculcated into
the bureaucracy, into the armed forces,
into the police police forces, they are
trained.
They are trained to obey the right kind
of authority.
So, when there's a new prime minister or
president who takes power, you obey that
person.
And if you stop obeying, then the whole
country falls apart.
So, when somebody takes takes over as a
new president, you don't have to go and
physically grab somebody's throat to
take control.
You are automatically in control the
moment you become the president. And
then if you show if you demonstrate
that you mean business and you are
competent and you are taking the country
in the right direction, then the control
and authority becomes even more
powerful.
That's how it is done.
Now, when there's an election in India
and somebody becomes MLA
or chief minister, don't they
automatically take control of the police
force of the state?
It's automatic.
That's how it goes.
But if you are in an African country in
a dictatorship, then you have to use
other means and then that's where you
have to really understand what power
means. What is power? How does somebody
in a lawless country acquire power and
and control and a militia and armed
force or whatever? Well, that's a whole
different story. We are not discussing
that today. But that will actually teach
you what power is.
What is the true nature and meaning of
power?
UMXG lol lol haha says, why does India
not have one unified script we ever had?
India is a gigantic
landmass. It is a subcontinent.
It is not a nation with 10,000 or 20,000
or 100,000 people.
It's a civilization.
That's why we've had multiple scripts
always have
we've always had multiple scripts
always.
Right?
That's actually
something that makes India great as
opposed to weak.
But you can have one
script for the national or
civilizational language.
You see, we have so many scripts in
India, right?
For example, we have the Tamil script,
we have the Telugu script, we have the
Kannada script.
We have the old Brahmi script. We have
the Devanagari script. We have the
Gurmukhi script. You can write Tamil in
Devanagari.
You can write Hindi in the Tamil script.
This is all interchangeable.
It's actually wonderful the kind of
system that we have.
UMXG lol haha says, many temples get
huge inflows, yet are overcrowded and
poorly managed.
Extreme rush. Police pushing devotees,
barely a glimpse of the idol. People
question the purpose of worship now and
some some even convert because of this.
Thoughts?
You know, what you're saying is true.
Lots of temples, especially the big
ones, the famous ones,
first of all, they are now managed by
the government.
The government controls the temples.
Um what you see typically is that
the temples are not very clean. The
surroundings are very cramped.
There's a lot of uncleanliness around in
the surroundings. There's huge queues
and the queues are shepherded through
these narrow passages and people are
mistreated.
And the moment you see the murti the
idol, you're given like 3 seconds to
take a darshan if even that is too high
too much and then you're pushed away.
Move on. Move on. Move on. Move on. Keep
going. That's not how it's things are
are supposed to be done.
That's that's just wrong.
Yeah.
So,
it doesn't mean that worship is not to
be done.
My point is okay, let's So, the reason
for this is because is that
today you don't have kings or emperors
who take care of these things. Kings and
emperors were invested in our culture
and civilization. They understood the
the of the devotees. They understood how
things are to be done. Today, it's the
government of India. The government of
India is a secular entity. It doesn't
care about culture, civilization,
feelings of people, whatever. It cares
about extracting money from temples.
That's all.
That's why things are so bad. But, does
it mean you should stop worship? You
should you should convert to a different
religion. What utter nonsense.
You can have your own murti in your home
and pray.
Or go to your local temple.
It's the same God, right?
So, I don't get why people are so
so low-IQ and stupid that because you
have the situation, because the
government mismanages and hijacks our
temples, that's why we should convert to
a different religion. That is seriously
only word I have is stupid.
James. James, my dear friend James.
James, my good chap.
James says, "English remains the
dominant language in the world for a
reason. It is clearly more superior,
best-sounding,
easy to learn. We developed the modern
world for you. You were stuck in the
past criticizing a language, just a tool
of communication."
English.
Easy to learn.
Easy to learn. Okay.
Let's say you use the
Let's let's examine a few words in the
English language. English.
Can.
Can, right? A can. Can of tomatoes, can
of whatever, can of beans. Can. What's
the plural of can?
Cans.
C A N, can. Plural is C A N S, cans.
Man.
M A N, man. What's the plural? Should be
mans, right? But, it's not mans. It's
men.
M E N, men.
Uh where's the logic?
Right? Where's the logic?
Can, cans. Man, men. What about woman?
Well, it's not womens.
It's women.
How how how does that work?
And you don't say women
men, so it should be women, but it's
women.
Women.
But, the spelling is W O M E N.
So, if the spelling is W O M E N, should
be women.
Like M E N is men, so W O M E N should
be women, but it's it's women.
I mean, I could just go on and on.
There's no logic in the English
language. And the English language
doesn't even have its own script, by the
way. It uses the Latin script.
Um
So, it's actually a really comical
language, you know? It's it's the
language we use today because it's the
language of the dominant caste in the
world,
the ethnicity in the world, the Anglos.
And you guys rule the world right now,
which is why we use the language. Why do
I use the language? Well, I'll use the
language of the oppressor, too,
to speak about the oppressor.
Right?
Uh yeah, so that's that's the thing.
Um it is the dominant language in the
world today, no question about that. Is
it superior? No, it's superior because
you guys have historically the past 500
years been superior in the organized
application and use of violence. That's
why your language is the dominant
language right now. Uh won't be that way
forever.
Anyhow, James, always good to have you.
Karan says, "Please Google the
Gowharshad Mosque,
Shah Abbas Mosque,
Sheikh Lotf
Lotfollah Mosque, Sultani Dome,
Samarkand Mosques.
The domes
closely resemble the Taj Mahals and were
built centuries before it."
Gowharshad Mosque is Gowharshad was the
wife of
Shahrukh,
the Turkic king
of Persia. Okay.
Let's see.
So, you're trying to I understand what
you're doing. You're trying to debunk
uh the logic that I have used that uh
the Taj Mahal is not Islamic
architecture, it's Indian or
Persian-influenced architecture. You're
saying before the Taj Mahal, you had
other things like this.
Wonderful. Okay. Okay, let's see.
Gowhar
Gowharshad
Mosque.
What's it look like?
Does this look like the Taj Mahal? The
dome.
The dome. I Look, this is not Arabic
architecture. This is Persian
architecture. Okay, even though the
Gowharshad was the wife of a Turk. Now,
you had Gowharshad Mosque, you have Shah
What about the Shah
Abbas.
Sorry, Abbas.
Shah Mosque, Isfahan. Again, Persian
architecture, not Arabic architecture.
Uh this just don't understand
the logic in people's minds. Sheikh Lotf
Sheikh
Lotfollah Mosque. Where is this?
Uh which part of the world is it in?
Sheikh Lotfollah Mosque.
It's uh Isfahan. Isfahan. So, once
again, Persian architecture, not Arabic
architecture.
Um
Sultani Sultani is going to be again
Persian. Samarkand.
Samarkand Mosque. Let me tell you
something, my dear friends.
Okay, Samarkand Mosque is this one. Oh,
sorry, it was on the screen. Okay.
Samarkand Mosque is this thing. Okay?
These mosques in Samarkand were built by
Indian slaves, by the way. Of FYI.
Okay? These mosques were built by Indian
slaves. I will I will prove it to you
once again. This is the Sheikh Lotfollah
Mosque with the those domes. Then you
have Shah Abbas Mosque in Isfahan with
that dome.
Then you have the Gowharshad Mosque.
Gowharshad was the wife of Shahrukh, the
Turkic king of Persia, who was an
invader, just like Aurangzeb.
So, you're trying to say that you had
these mosques that predated the Taj
Mahal and they have these domes, which
is why my my claim that these dome
structures are not Islamic architecture
is wrong.
Which is totally incorrect. Your your
argument is incorrect because this is
Persian architecture. Persian
architecture is not Arabic architecture.
I have shown in a previous episode that
Arabic architecture is all rectangles
and flat stuff. There are no domes
there.
The domes came from India and Persia.
Persia is an offshoot of of India.
Okay?
Now, let me show you something else
which is more interesting. This is okay.
Your
attempt to debunk me has not really
worked. But, let me show you something
interesting. Something that is genuinely
interesting.
Okay?
Once again, let us go to my Twitter
account.
And let us search for the word mosque.
Mosque in my Twitter account.
Um not that, not that. Look at this.
This is the Masjid-i-Kabul,
the Blue Mosque in Tabriz, Iran. What do
you see?
You see swastikas
on a mosque in Persia,
in Iran. Blue Mosque in Iran.
This is the Poi Kalyan Mosque in
Uzbekistan. What do you see?
You see a swastika-like design.
This is a mosque in
Kashgar,
present-day China. What do you see on
the floor?
A swastika design.
Let me show you more.
Zharkent Mosque, Kazakhstan.
Swastikas.
Swastikas. Swastikas.
Swastic.
What else do we have? Uh
the Mosque of Aya Sophia. Well, it used
to be a church. This is Byzan- Byzantine
art.
Okay? Let me show you more.
The Grand Mosque of Cordoba in Spain.
Was it Yeah, there there are swastikas
there.
Then you have the Kalyan Mosque in
Bukhara,
Uzbekistan.
What do you have here?
You have swastikas. Let me show you
more.
This is the Bibi-Khanym Mosque in
Samarkand, Uzbekistan.
You will see swastikas
over here.
And if that's not the case, well, what
do we have here? The Mosque of Khoja
Ahmed
Yasawi.
Once again, swastika.
What have we here? The Masjid-i-Jameh in
Yazd, Iran.
What do you have? Swastikas.
I'll show you more.
Bibi-Khanym Mosque,
Uzbekistan, Samarkand.
Swastikas.
Uh Jameh Mosque, Isfahan.
I mean, I could go on and on.
Khoja Ahmed Yasawi and so on.
Um Azad.
Uh one second. Okay?
This is
the Islamic Azad University, Tehran.
What do you see there?
Swastikas.
Uh let's see Timur, okay? One second.
Timur.
Timur Timur.
You see this? This is the tomb of
Timur.
And what you will find here
is swastikas.
So,
who built these monuments.
Indian slaves.
So, all So, yeah. Once again, coming
back to your argument, really, please.
Please give me a better argument.
If you want to debunk me, sure. Please.
If I'm wrong, I'm I'm happy to accept
I'm wrong. But, better arguments,
please. Better logic. Thank you. Suraj
says, claims that Okay, once again.
Once again, someone's trying to debunk
what I said.
Okay.
DNA is
DNA
DNA results. Show me Saddam Hussein's
DNA results.
It is alleged that the Americans So, the
Let me read this out. Claims that Saddam
was of Indian descent were pushed by
opponents like extremist Khazal
al-Ghazali. DNA results instead showed
45% Arab, 30% Persian, 15% Mesopotamian,
and the rest Caucasian. Rarely
disappointed. So, Suraj is rarely rarely
disappointed with me, but today he's
super disappointed.
Saddam Hussein, it is alleged his DNA
was tested by Americans. Obviously, he
was their captive, they would have done
it. But, have they ever published it?
They have never published it.
So, where did you come up with these
figures? That's disappointing.
How did you come up with these figures?
45% Arab, 30% Where did you come up with
this?
His DNA results are secret.
The Americans won't publish that.
So, how do you have it? Please explain
to me.
Next.
Abhishek Shrivastav, Grok uploads bikini
pics is era of dangerous AI begin.
This is actually not dangerous AI. This
is just cringe-worthy AI.
Everyone I mean, if you go to go on
Twitter, half the people there are
saying, "Please put a bikini on this."
or "Please put a bikini on that." Elon
Musk is encouraging that.
Anyway, that's just
cringe-worthy, I would say.
What's the point?
This is not dangerous AI. This is
cringe-worthy AI. It's just AI in bad
taste. Imagine how much computing power
goes into creating these stupid bikini
pics.
This is the problem with humanity.
You create the most advanced technology,
and people will will use it for idiotic
purposes.
What can I say? Jimmy Thank you. Well,
thank you very much. Thank you so much.
Thank you very much, sir. Jimmy Lee.
Jimmy Lee, thank you.
Prathap Dana says, identity of Kassite
invaders of Babylon. Names sound Vedic.
Bugash Baga, Maruttash Marutas,
Abirattash Abiratta. They appeared
around 1600 BC. Yeah, so there's this
bunch of people who who suddenly appear
in West Asia.
See, what we find
chronologically, it makes a lot of
sense. Just give me a second.
Um
This is imported from Targoviste in
Transylvania Transylvania. Okay.
So, around 2000 BC
something really interesting happens
in West Asia.
The interesting thing thing that happens
in West Asia around 2000 BC
is that there is this sudden
introgration,
means appearance in West Asia
of Indian Zebu cattle.
Zebu cattle are of Indian origin.
Before 2000 BC, there were there were no
Zebu cattle in West Asia. Suddenly,
around 2000 BC
you find Zebu cattle in West Asia.
And suddenly, around the same time, 2000
BC
we find
paintings or or or etchings
of Zebu cattle in Egypt.
So, clearly, Indians appeared in West
Asia around 2000 BC.
And that's where you have
the emergence
of
Aryan or Indo-Aryan kingdoms and
empires. The Mitanni The Mitanni empire
was very clearly Indian. The aristocracy
or royalty was Indian.
Um the Hittites, once again, the royalty
was Indian.
And possibly, the Kassites.
Right? Their names also sound Vedic.
So, it's possible the Kassites were also
of Indian origin. Maybe Indians reached
this region and set up multiple kingdoms
that were perhaps
roughly contemporaneous with with each
other, and maybe spread out across the
region. Some in Anatolia, some in the
Syria region, some further east of
Syria, which is present-day Mesopotamia
that that region, Babylon.
Yeah?
Uh but, Western historians will mostly
try their best to deny the Indian
origins. But, they can't in the case of
the Hittites and the Mitanni because
they were so clearly Indo-Aryan.
And not just Indo-Aryan, but Hindu.
Uh but, the Kassites kind of it's still
kind of disputed. But, most likely,
yeah, based on the names you're giving
us, mhm. Let's see if if you have some
other names of the Kassites Kassite
Kassite Kassite rulers.
Uh Kassites.
Okay, let's go to Wikipedia. Or, let's
go to
We'll go to Wikipedia. Even though it's
not necessarily a good source of
information.
Um yeah, so you can see there's
along the two rivers.
Uh the Tigris and the Euphrates.
And
uh what are the names of their kings?
Karru
Kurru
Kurduniash
Kassite term used for the kingdom. Okay.
Um Amarna letters.
Labaya was a Canaanite prince. Do we
have the names of some of their kings?
Kassite deities. Uh language isolate.
Okay, so
the Kassite language
the origin is uncertain.
Some people have even linked it to
Sanskrit, but that is obviously not the
according to Wikipedia.
Uh the Kassite the Kassite deities. What
are the deities?
Um
disproved theories. So, disproved
theories means they cannot be the,
you know, Greek Boreas or Vedic Maruts,
etc. Can't be India. India cannot be the
the case ever.
So, yeah.
If you look at the Western
interpretations, India is never going to
figure in these things, but
it's it's possible that they could be of
Indian origin based on the
evidence that we have
and the interlinkages between the
evidence.
King Ritwik says, best Balochistan
scenario favoring India. One,
independent country. Second, becomes a
part of Iran, which is enemy of USA.
Third, currently part of occupied
Balochistan.
Best scenario for India.
So, if Balochistan becomes a remains
part of Pakistan, then the people of
Balochistan will remain will continue to
be oppressed.
And of course, um
uh
they will do their best to
damage Pakistani interests.
If Balochistan becomes independent
If Balochistan becomes independent, it
means Pakistan has broken up.
Okay?
Without Pakistan breaking up completely,
Balochistan doesn't become independent.
Becomes part of Iran, which is part
enemy of the I would say the best case
scenario is independent Balochistan,
which means Pakistan has broken up
completely. That is the best case
scenario for India. Best scenario
favoring India.
Balochistan will not be independent in
Pakistan the rest of Pakistan remains
united. It's not possible at all.
So.
Prathap Dana says, Venezuela operation
looks staged as hell. Oh, it's it's
clearly an inside job of some kind.
There was some kind of backroom deal
somewhere. Look,
it's very clear now that the American
helicopters went in, took Mr. Maduro,
abducted him and his wife, and took them
to New York. Uh first, took him to the
USS Iwo Jima,
and from there to New York.
Now, when the American helicopters are
flying over Caracas, the capital of
Venezuela,
how come there was no air defense
activity? How come there were no
anti-aircraft missiles fired? How come
there was no anti-aircraft fire you
know, gunfire? Nothing.
It's like they just allowed them to come
in and take over and take the guy and
leave.
So, clearly, the Americans first made a
deal
with the Socialist Party of Venezuela,
the key people in that, and the key
people in the Venezuelan military. They
bribed them or whatever.
Or threatened them. Or maybe a
combination of bribing and threatening.
So,
the key people
in power in Venezuela in the in the
military and the in politics
knew, and they had agreed with the US.
This is what's going to happen. We're
going to allow you to take him,
and then we're going to cooperate with
you, and you make us rich.
Clearly, that's what happened.
So, the the regime change is very weird.
They just take out the main guy, and now
the so the the vice president is now the
person in power, that lady,
and she's going to cooperate with the
US. She's going to give them all the oil
they want and everything they want. So,
it's like the US has its own client
state now
in Venezuela.
That's it. Done deal.
Outstanding. Well done.
Ritwik Pawar says, do nukes give a 100%
guarantee to that a country cannot be
invaded? Hypothetically, if Venezuela
had nuclear weapons, would they dare
Would the US dare to invade? Well,
that's a very pertinent question, and
that brings me to the tweet that I have
made today.
So, let me find the tweet and put that
on the screen, and then discuss.
Then we shall discuss
and examine this issue. So, where is my
Twitter account? Let me open this. One
second. What was that?
Um
Give me a second.
Okay. So, let's go to my my Twitter
account.
Let's put that on the screen.
And
So, this is the tweet.
To all Indians rejoicing in
our sovereignty because we have nuclear
weapons, a sobering thought.
Nuclear weapons are necessary for
sovereignty,
but not sufficient.
You need the right leadership.
The wrong leadership may end up
surrendering your nukes to the enemy.
Case in point, Ukraine 1996.
Ukraine is a great example. Ukraine had
nukes until 1996. They were Soviet
nukes, but the Ukrainians had nukes.
And they gave up those nukes
to the Russians to be dismantled or to
for whatever the Russians wanted to do.
And that's why the Ukraine situation
exists today. If the Ukrainians had
nukes until the 21st century,
they would not have had to become a
client state of the US,
and they would not have been a situation
where there's a war today.
So, do nukes
So, if the Ukrainians had nukes, things
would have been different. Now, coming
to the question about nukes actually.
So, if you have nukes, let's say you are
India. You have nukes.
Does it guarantee that that your country
won't be invaded?
We just discussed Venezuela, right?
Venezuela had air defenses. Venezuela
had Sukhois. They had all kinds of
weapons.
But when the Americans invaded and came
for Maduro, not a single weapon was
used. Nothing was used.
What's the point of having weapons if
you won't use them? So, why were the
weapons not used?
Because the Americans reached some kind
of deal, secret deal with the key people
in power in the
in the Venezuelan Venezuelan ruling
party
and the military.
So, what if you are a nation with nukes
and your enemy, whoever they are,
they bribe your leaders
and your key people
that we're going to come and invade your
country. We're going to give you as much
money as you want. Don't use your nukes.
Then what happens?
Your nukes are worthless then.
Your nukes are utterly worthless if your
leaders
don't have principles and will be bribed
and will be will be bought.
Then they will allow the enemy to
invade, and then they will hand over the
nukes on a platter to your enemy.
So, you need nukes, but you also need
the right leadership.
Please understand that.
Okay.
Who I don't know how to
pronounce that. Is it Yeah. What's the
history of the Mundari tribe in South
Sudan? Are they related to Hindu
culture? I don't know about the history
of the Mundari tribe.
So, that's the that's that's the problem
with history.
If I if I
When it comes to geopolitics, everything
is logical.
And if you know the broad strokes
history of the world, then you
understand geopolitics. When when it
comes to history, if you ask me a
specific question about some tribe or
some dynasty somewhere, I may have
absolutely no idea about it. So, I have
not studied the history of the Mundari
tribe in South Sudan.
I have no idea what their culture is
like, what their history is like.
So, unfortunately, I can't answer your
question because I don't have the
information. Sorry.
Sorry.
King Ritwik says, "Isn't a Venezuela
type situation not at all possible in
Iran and North Korea because these two
countries are dictatorships. You cannot
do an inside job."
Let's say you have a dictatorship.
Okay?
So, in a dictatorship,
you have
one person who is in a in the position
of being the over
the the the overall boss.
That's the face of the dictatorship.
Dictatorship has a face. In China, it is
Mr. Xi Jinping. In North Korea, it is
Mr. Kim Jong-un.
Et cetera.
So, in a dictator
you have the key person, the face.
But that one person doesn't have all the
power.
Please understand this, my dear
children.
That one person doesn't have all the
power.
That one person relies on an inner
circle of people
who share power with him.
But this person at the top
has mastered the politics which keeps
him
in power at at the number one position.
He's able to play everybody
off against each other.
And he understands the system better
than anybody else. And he is seen as the
person even through by the inner circle
as the person who he who gives everybody
the best chance of success.
That's why that person is in power or is
the face of the dictatorship.
But there'll be 20, 30, 50, maybe 100
people in the inner circle who are
almost equally powerful
and who have their own ambitions.
So, in a dictatorship,
let's say I have so-and-so leader.
And that person, let's say they have an
inner circle of 50 people.
And under the 50 people, you have 2,000
people. Under those 2,000, you got
20,000 and so on. It's a pyramidal
structure.
All you have to do is to bribe the right
people.
In a democracy, it's very difficult. In
a dictatorship, it's way easier.
Okay?
It's way easier.
Actually,
if
Yeah, it's it's actually way easier.
So, if you can promise those people,
you know, wealth, power, privilege,
riches,
then you may be able to
break the country.
Uh destroy the dictatorship without
having to fire a shot.
So, that's possible. It's definitely
possible in Iran and North Korea. In
North Korea, it may be difficult because
it's a very insular country.
It's not a country that's very
doesn't have a great interface with the
world. It's kind of insulated from the
world. Iran is less insular than North
Korea.
So, Iran, it's it's actually easier.
North Korea is harder.
Amisha Mishra says, "No nation has the
guts to say anything to the US. Even
China, Russia are just condemning no
action." Of course, no action. Don't you
think other powerful nations will follow
the same thing? Which thing?
Don't you think other powerful nation
will follow the same thing?
You mean do what the US did? Yeah, if
you can get away with it, you will do
it. The US is the most powerful nation.
I mean, what happened yesterday has
shown the world where the real power
lies.
Can China take Taiwan?
They dare not.
Can Russia take the rest of Ukraine?
They right now want to fight a slow war.
It's in their benefit to fight a slow
war, not to take the whole nation in 2
weeks.
Ukraine.
US goes and gets what it wants. Done
deal. End of story. Ukraine is
Venezuela is is solved.
That's what real power is.
When you have real power, you don't have
to give reasons. You don't have to
justify anything. You don't have to give
excuses. Yeah.
You have to kind of justify, and your
justification can be completely
ridiculous like the US justification for
Venezuela, but it doesn't matter.
And nobody will condemn.
So, various
world leaders have kind of issued
expressed some reservations that this
was not entirely according to
international law and so on so forth. We
are concerned about this with the kind
of precedent it sets and so on and so
on, but it's all verbal.
Nobody has taken any action against the
US.
Even Russia and China have simply
expressed their disappointment,
dissatisfaction. Some of them China has
condemned what's happened.
But it's just curry in the It's just
words.
They can't take any action. It
demonstrates who is way more powerful
than everybody else.
The US is way more powerful than China
or Russia.
India has simply said that we are
monitoring the situation. That's
effectively that's what we have said. We
are concerned and we are we are
monitoring the situation.
Yeah.
So, that is the situation. Now, do I
think other powerful nations will follow
the same thing? Yeah, if you can get get
away with it, you will do it.
So,
the question is who is powerful in this
manner?
Can China do the same thing to Taiwan?
They can't.
Taiwan is in their backyard, but they
can't do it.
The US is so powerful.
Uh Russia could try to do that against
Zelenskyy potentially.
We'll see. We'll wait and watch.
So, this sets a precedent.
According to international law, you
can't do such things. You have to
respect other nations' sovereignty. You
may not like the nation. You may not
like the president, but you can't behave
in this manner. Otherwise, the entire
edifice of international order breaks
down.
But the situation is that the US has
done it. Others won't be allowed to do
it.
So, yeah. That's where we are. And that
demonstrates where the real power lies
in the world.
Shubrat Shukla says, "Japan and South
Korea TFR is low because of overwork.
Then what's wrong with Europe since they
are not over worked at all." See, it's
not always just one cause.
There is a multiplicity of causes that
come together to create a situation.
But sometimes one factor predominates
over the others.
One factor is overwork.
You are working so hard. Everybody has
to work so hard to have an income
that you just don't have the time to
procreate.
The husband and the wife are both
working in separate jobs.
Everyone both are working 12 hours a
day.
Six days a week, six and a half days a
week, then how will they ever have the
time to procreate?
That's one factor.
Another factor
is the cost of living.
Let's say you are not working 12 hours a
day. You are in Europe, you're working
40 hours a week, five days a week
maximum.
But the cost of living is incredibly
high.
So you can live a nice life peacefully.
But if you have a kid,
then the cost of medical treatment is
incredibly high, astronomically high.
Medical treatment is not always
available when you need it. Then the
cost of schooling is incredibly high.
And the cost of higher education is even
more even higher.
So that's one scenario. I'm not saying
every nation has a scenario. There are
multiple factors that come together.
Then there are the social there's the
social situation.
There's immigration.
Immigrants are violent. You're scared to
expose your children to such such a
world. So some people say we'll not have
kids.
There are multiple factors
that come together
to create a situation. It's not just one
factor. Please, let's analyze things in
more detail.
Surface level analysis is never good.
Fast snail says, could this impact
Canadian oil and Keystone pipeline?
Could what impact?
Venezuela.
Uh what's the Keystone pipeline? Are you
talking about Venezuela?
What happened in Venezuela? Is that what
you're talking about? I suppose you must
be talking about that.
Um
um could this impact Canadian oil and
Keystone pipeline?
If the US takes over Venezuela, could
that impact Can- What is the
Look,
one second. Let me see what is the
Keystone pipeline.
Um Keystone, k e y s t o n e pipeline.
Where is this Keystone pipeline?
Network transporting crude oil from
Alberta to Yeah. From Canada to the US.
Okay.
Um I'm not sure how it impacts Canada
and the Keystone pipeline. I'm I'm not
really sure.
Um okay.
So I'm I'm not sure how this was better.
Uh how how it would impact the Keystone
pipeline.
Right next.
BG Sekar says, most of the revolutions
actually produced huge amount of deaths
and economic and political instability.
But still people today feel excited by
hearing the word revolution. Why?
Because people have learned about the
word revolution in a textbook
sitting in a classroom.
And they have been taught about
revolution, what revolution means, by
some professor, by some teacher.
And your textbooks and your teachers and
professors will conveniently
omit
what revolutions really are. Revolutions
are bloody, violent, chaotic affairs.
They cause a tremendous amount of damage
to society,
to your nation.
If there's a revolution in your nation,
you will end up losing territory. Other
nations will come and bite into your
territories. You're going to have
tremendous violence and destruction in
society.
You're going to have bloodshed.
And at the end of the revolution, if the
revolution succeeds,
who's going to end up leading the
country? The leaders of the revolution.
Who are the typically the leaders of a
revolution? The most violent people are
the leaders of a revolution.
Yeah. So that's how it generally goes.
But none of that is ever taught.
If you are taught about the French
Revolution, they will teach you about
liberty, equality, fraternity, the
wonderful ideas of the French
Revolution.
They will not they will give some
account of the reign of terror about
what Robespierre did and some something
about the guillotine, but it will not
really
you know
convey the horror
and the devastation
to those who study it.
So that's why and and and if your if
your textbook is written from a Marxist
perspective and if your professors have
the Marxist ideology in their bloods, my
goodness, they're going to glorify
revolutions and portray it as something
wonderful.
So that's why people who study things
from textbooks and in classrooms without
actually interfacing the real world,
they'll think revolutions are wonderful
things. That's the
situation.
Sushant Gurjar says, the main reason for
different empires occupying us in the
past 1,000 years was not only that we
were divided, but we did not have
shatrubodh.
Which is still the case. What are your
thoughts on this? Yeah, this word has
become very popular these days in Indian
circles.
Shatrubodh.
Actually,
there is
a significant element of truth to this.
Um
so you have to understand the enemy.
You have to understand those who seek to
destroy our society, destroy our culture
and civilization.
You have to study them.
The way you would see a the way you
would
study a virus or a bacterium.
You have to study them. You have to
understand their characteristics. You
have to understand their mechanism
of action.
You have to understand their
pathologies.
You have to understand their true
nature. You have to understand what they
truly seek to do to seek to do.
Right? That's what you have to do.
And in India it's been like, you know,
we did not bother to to study the
adversaries properly, what their true
intentions and motives were.
Uh and here it is still the case. It is
still the case because we are all
educated in classrooms from textbooks.
And your classroom in the classroom your
teacher will not tell you
the what the real world is like and what
the real what the national interest is,
what the civilizational interest is, and
what the enemies of nation and
civilization are. And what they seek to
do and what are their characteristics.
None of this this is taught
today.
So that's why we have to educate
ourselves on our own.
These are my thoughts on this.
Shravya K says, what caused USA Mexico
war? Why USA not annex Mexico?
The USA was a territor- territory-hungry
nation.
It wanted more territory. It found the
justification, the pretext
for a war with Mexico and grabbed more
territory. Colorado, Texas Texas,
California, etc.
It took all the nice territory and as
you go further south, the territory
becomes more desertified and and hotter.
And they did not want all that
territory. They got all the nice big
territory. Texas is huge. Arizona,
Colorado is huge. California is
gigantic, beautiful.
So much prime territory was taken. New
Mexico,
and all of that. I mean, if you look at
the map of the United States. Okay?
Um
First of all, let's see, okay.
US Mexico war, 1846, right?
Okay, map before and after.
So
can you see the map? How much how how
large Mexico was?
And all of that
green territory like half of it was
taken over by the US.
Um
yeah, this kind of gives you an idea.
I'm I'm one second. This probably gives
you an idea.
So the Americans found a pretext to go
to war with Mexico and they took
took away took over about half of the
territory of Mexico. Eventually, as you
go further south, there's desert, the
Sonoran Desert, and so on, and that's
something the US did not want. Baja
California, they said let it remain with
Mexico and so on. So
yeah.
EKS Bogga says, why was China's envoy in
Venezuela? I'm not sure.
I'm not sure. I did not I did not look
into that. The envoy was in Mexico
in Venezuela yesterday.
A delegation was in Mexico in Venezuela
yesterday. Why was that the case? I have
not looked into it.
Could be routine
consultations.
Could be something else. I am not really
sure. It doesn't really matter at this
point.
Doesn't really matter at this point.
Um
Shankar Mahadevan says, Indian
government compromised on the Starlink
part. Explain.
Look,
I don't know
whether the Indian government is
comprom- compromised on Starlink or not.
What is my position on Starlink? My
position has been clear from the
beginning.
India should not allow Starlink to
operate within Indian territory.
As simple as that. That has always been
my position from the from the beginning,
before people even started talking about
Starlink potentially coming to India.
Starlink should not be allowed to
operate within India. It will be used in
the future
in operations to potentially destabilize
or break India if it is allowed to
operate in India.
Yeah, so we should give Starlink
permission to operate
in India. As simple as that.
And I hope that the government of India
will make the right decision.
Um okay. Died in plane crash says the UA
media.
Ukrainian media
outlet claimed that claimed Buryats are
weaker than Ukrainian soldiers in
Ukraine's Pravda and Pravda means truth.
Okay, Pravda means truth.
And Ukrainska Pravda means Ukrainian
truth.
And that media outlet called Ukrainska
Pravda say claimed that Buryats are
weaker than Ukrainian soldiers.
Isn't it ironic? Well, it's it's it's
propaganda.
Propaganda is is a legitimate part of
warfare.
It is what it is.
P Cole says, "Could you please explain
the concept of Greater Israel?
Will it be a reality as we know that
Israel has never really defined its
official borders and in every war it
takes some land of the opposition
opposite nation. I have not looked into
this matter of Greater Israel. Does it
even really exist? Is it just uh
a myth? I don't know.
I am not aware
of whether this is an official position
of Israel, whether it is some kind of
secret
aspiration. I I am not sure.
How large could put this potential
hypothetical Greater Israel be?
I don't know.
So, I do not know about this.
I will not be able to explain because I
have not looked into this. I am not sure
if it is
even a real thing.
There's plenty of these conspiracies on
social media these days.
A lot of people are claiming that Israel
wants to seek seek more territory.
But has Israel ever given an official
statement about this?
Do you have any official document about
this? If there is no official statement,
if there are no official documents of
any kind,
then it's just mere speculation, right?
It's just mere speculation.
Like there are people in India who want
Akhand Bharat.
But is Akhand Bharat an official
position of the government of India?
Has the government of India ever put out
any document
that confirms that we seek to expand our
territories? The government of India has
never made this any kind of
official position.
And that's why I would say that this
concept of Akhand Bharat, it is not an
official position of the government of
India. It is merely the the dream of
many Indians.
Similarly, such a thing could be the
dream of many Israelis. I don't know
about that.
I'm speculating maybe many Israelis want
something like this. What are the
contours of Greater Israel? What
territories do they want as part of
Greater Israel if it is is a thing? I
don't know.
So, my explanation is going to be that
this is not an official position of the
government of Israel, just like Akhand
Bharat is not an official position of
the government of India.
And whatever is being
spoken about, it is mere speculation.
That is all I can say. Beyond that, I I
don't know anything else.
Bijus Aika says, "We don't have any
Chinese diaspora. Then how Chinese
cuisine came to India and mixed India?"
Who says we don't have a Chinese
diaspora?
India has a Chinese diaspora.
Of course India has a Chinese diaspora.
Come on.
Have you heard of the the the the the
actor singer Meiyang Chang?
Who is Meiyang Chang?
He's an Indian actor and television
host.
Okay?
Um
He's a third generation Indian Chinese
with roots in China's Hubei Hubei
province. Who are the Indian Chinese
people?
Communities of Han Chinese, not Tibetan
Han Chinese origin.
Permanent communities descended from
immigrants and refugees from China.
Uh they came during British colonial
rule, the British occupy occupation of
India.
So, we have
a Chinese diaspora in India.
Some of them live in Kolkata. Some of
them live in other major cities in
India.
And uh I think the the very famous dish
called Manchurian,
Manchurian chicken or whatever it is
called,
was invented by one of these uh
Indians of Chinese origin.
It has nothing to do with Manchuria. It
is not a Chinese dish, but it's today a
very popular Indo-Chinese dish, right?
So, we have a Chinese diaspora in India.
And I think it is they who introduced
this Chinese cuisine which has become an
Indo-Chinese cuisine which is different
from mainstream regular Chinese cuisine,
but maybe more popular than regular than
authentic Chinese cuisine, right?
So,
uh why no other mixture like
Indo-Chinese food has succeeded?
Well, Chinese food is great. Chinese
cuisine is great. And if you combine
that with Indian spices and flavors and
all, it becomes even more interesting.
That's why it's successful. I suppose if
you try to
create Indo-French food,
it may be successful.
I mean, French cuisine, if you add
Indian spices to it, I think it'll be
good. It it could be good perhaps. I
nobody's ever tried, I suppose.
Yeah?
I'm sure many other fusion experiments
will succeed.
We have something called East African
food,
which is
food of East Africa, which is very
heavily influenced by India. So, they
use all kinds of Indian spices. That's
again fusion cuisine.
I suppose all kinds of
you know, fusion cuisines could succeed,
but
for some reason
Indo-Chinese has been the most
successful. I'm not sure exactly why
it's the only one that's so successful.
Mm but yeah.
AKS Bagga says,
"Check Russian oligarch Oleg Poston,
Venezuela, please." Oleg who?
Oleg is a first name. There are millions
of Oleg's in the world.
What's Oleg's surname?
Okay, let me see who is this Russian
oligarch Oleg.
Russian
[Music]
oligarch
Oleg, who is that?
Oleg Deripaska?
Oleg Tinkov?
Look,
I don't know which one is it.
Oleg Deripaska, is it?
Let's see. Oleg Deripaska.
Look, if you want me to do something
just give me the proper the details,
right?
Tinkov.
Does he have a Twitter? He's got a
YouTube.
Oleg Deripaska has Instagram.
You talking about
Instagram? You talking about Twitter?
You talking about Facebook?
Okay, the instructions are unclear. The
directions are not clear. I will not be
able to
I'm not going to go on a wild goose
chase over here, right?
You want me to do something, I'll be
happy to do it, but give me the details.
Oleg what?
What's his full name? That much you can
give me, yes? Is that too much to ask?
Seriously, come on.
Please, please help me out here.
Please help me out.
Here is Mantikor says, "A global short
circuit is being enforced on the PC
industry due to AI race. Price of RAM is
increasing daily.
This will continue for the next decade.
What opportunity does it give India and
why?" Look,
why is the price of RAM shooting up?
Because there's a bunch of
idiots on Twitter on X who are saying,
"Put a bikini on this. Put a bikini on
that."
Hm?
And that's why
all the computing power is being used up
for putting bikinis on people's images.
Anyway, that's what it is. So, uh the
price of RAM is is shooting up. It's
increasing, no question.
And that's why the price prices of PCs
is going to go up
proportionately.
And this is going to continue. What
opportunity does it give India and why?
Does India manufacture RAM?
If India manufactures RAM, it will be
good for India. It will give it will
give India higher revenue.
Does India manufacture RAM chips? I'm
not sure we do. Let me see.
Does India I don't think we do.
Does India manufacture
RAM chips?
I don't think so.
I don't think so. Okay, India is just
beginning
to manufacture RAM chips. Sahastra
Semiconductors
uh microSDs late 2023 semiconductor
mission etc. microSD cards.
Memory chips, microSD cards. I'm talking
about RAM over here.
RAM.
Memory chips and RAM. Can is microSD
cards be used for RAM?
Okay, I'm not really sure about that.
Can microSD cards can
can micro can SD cards
cards be used for RAM?
No, you can't. So, what is this answer
like? So, it doesn't look like we are
manufacturing RAM chips.
MicroSD cards are not RAM chips. You can
use SD to augment your RAM potentially
through using some software, but it's
not exactly a RAM chip, right?
Random access memory.
So, look, it will be an opportunity for
India if India becomes a player in the
RAM game. If India starts manufacturing
high quality RAM chips. Typically, you
have Seagate and Transcend and Nvidia
ad,
If you want RAM if you want to buy, you
know, RAM chips and you want to install
them into your laptop by opening up the
backside and doing that, if you want to
augment your RAM, you can
buy RAM chips from, you know,
reasonably expensive, but not too
expensive.
But India's not not in the game. So, if
India gets into the game and starts
manufacturing high-quality RAM chips
that are in demand in the world, then it
will be good for India.
Aditya Rahul says,
"How did 21-year-old Mehmet conquer
Constantinople, defeat Vlad the Impaler?
It's said that he fulfilled one of the
fulfilled fulfilled one of the
prophecies of Islam. One of the
prophecies of Islam was that somebody
some Islamic person will conquer the red
apple."
The red apple was Constantinople.
Now, how did he conquer Constantinople?
That's a long story, my dear friend. How
can I explain over here?
People make like seven seven episode
movie
TV series about that. How he conquered
Constantinople.
That's a long long story.
He needed an army for that. They had to
resort to all kinds of ingenious tricks.
They had to carry ships
overland
into the golden uh
golden horn, right?
Across that
the bridge. Not not the bridge, the
the golden horn, they call it.
It's it's a long story. It's a long
story. They needed gigantic cannons.
I think they employed a traitor
to make cannons for them, a Venetian or
or Christian traitor who was a
manufacturer of cannons and he made
gigantic cannons. That was one part of
the puzzle. The other puzzle part of the
puzzle was that the the the the the the
Byzantines had blockaded
uh let's go to the map.
They had shut off access to the golden
horn or something. So, that's why they
had to they had to carry ships overland.
We're talking about Istanbul, which is
Constantinople.
And we're talking about
the golden horn.
Okay? So, you have two bridges here.
Go away.
Galata
and whatever this is. So,
so this region was blockaded so that the
Turks could not enter into the golden
horn.
So, the Turks, what they did was that
they carried ships at at that time there
was forest over here. Okay? This was all
forest.
So, they they
they carried ships
overland into the golden horn.
And that created huge problems for the
defenders of Constantinople. Then
eventually they had to resort to heavy
cannon fusillades,
cannon uh cannon attacks on the walls on
the on the fortified walls and
eventually, after a long long long
siege,
the walls broke and they were able to
enter Constantinople and massacre
everybody
and so on. Long long story. Can't
explain like 2 minutes.
Bhaskar Gupta says,
"Minimum requirement to say two
countries are at war."
Minimum requirement to say that two
countries are at war. Uh it's an
interesting question. What's the minimum
threshold?
A kinetic action, I would say.
A prolonged kinetic action.
I mean, you can have an unstable border
where you have occasional maybe daily
firing against each other,
but uh the kinetic action, which is
that sort of thing, needs to
be it needs to extend beyond just the
border. It needs to go beyond that.
And it should be a prolonged affair,
something like that. I'm not sure
exactly what the requirements are.
I mean, some people would would would uh
argue that the three-day war that we
had, Operation Sindhu, doesn't entirely
fulfill the criteria of being an actual
war.
I'm not sure what the minimum criteria
are. I consider it to have been a
three-day war, an aerial war.
The navies were not involved the
infantry were not involved, but there
was an aerial war.
Uh mainly missiles, right?
So, I'm not sure what the exact even if
I'm not sure if criteria even exist.
I think eventually, once something
happens or once something has ended,
there is if there is a consensus that it
was a war, then it's a war.
But I would say there needs to be
kinetic action that is deeper, not just
shallow at the at the borders, and
should be prolonged and should be
serious, like serious targets. Then
maybe it's war.
Monish Sabrinath says, "What can the
government of India do to reduce for
reducing the cost of living, especially
in housing, groceries, education, and
health?"
Housing, groceries, education, health.
Well, I would say first of all, look,
this is an idealistic position I'm
taking over here, okay?
But according to me, in a civilized
society,
if the government is
taking taxes from the citizens,
then education and health care should be
entirely free.
Tax the citizens. I am not saying give
it for free.
Tax the citizens.
And use the taxpayer money
for giving free education and health
care. If
you want to be called a civilized
society.
Because that's what we always had
in in free India before India came under
foreign occupation.
Even during the British Raj, you had
Indian princely states that gave free
education and health health care. Do you
know that?
Even after independence for a year or
two,
you had some princely states, former
princely states in India, that still
gave free education and health care. And
high quality, not garbage like we have
today.
So, it can be done, very easily done
with the kind of taxation system that we
have.
Uh when it comes to housing, groceries,
etc. etc. etc.,
well, I would say if you want to reduce
the cost of everything,
destroy corruption.
All the costs will come down.
Start with that.
Then we'll talk about the other stuff.
Destroy, annihilate corruption.
The cost of everything will come down.
That's what the GOI can do.
Indian Navy says Rajat has 24 MH-60R. Is
that enough? What's the MH Is it the the
Chinook?
Is it the American Chinook?
Let's find out. MH
MH-60R.
What's the Sikorsky Seahawk? Seahawk.
Uh I think it's a liability.
Is it enough?
I think it's a liability. It's an
American helicopter.
An American helicopter will come with
all kinds of fantastic things that we
will not be aware of. It will have
backdoors. It will have kill switches.
And even if we ignore the backdoors and
kill switches, you will need spare
parts.
The spare parts will have to come from
the US.
And the US can deny it to you
whenever they feel like.
I think these purchases that we have
made from the Americans are all
liabilities.
Big liabilities.
Uh we do need naval helicopters.
I'm not sure how many we need.
24 of
a country like India,
the size of a subcontinent, we have 24.
Do you think it's enough?
We need more, way more, but not these.
We need to have our own helicopters. Why
can't we manufacture, design, and
manufacture our own? Why can't we?
Uh
Fast Snail says, "What happens to unused
Russian arms?" Why unused?
Now, can you please explain which unused
Russian arms?
Are you talking about Ukraine? Are you
talking about
Venezuela? Are you talking about India?
What are you talking about? Why don't
people give me context?
We have Russian arms in India.
They are not unused.
If you're talking about Ukraine,
uh sorry, if you're talking about
Venezuela,
they have Russian weapons.
Those were not used, right? When the
Americans invaded yesterday.
Why were they unused? Because the
Americans bribed the key people in the
government and the military to not use
these things. What happens to them now?
Well, we'll see.
We'll see about that.
Maybe the Americans will take them,
examine them, dismantle them, re-
reverse engineer them, you know,
try to
gather all the secrets.
They won't really work because these
will be export versions of whatever, but
we'll see.
Biju Saikia says, "Do you think
importance of romance is exaggerated in
pop culture? I mean, love life is
important, but it should not be anyone's
top priority." I agree.
It's it's obviously love is important,
romance is important in in life,
but at the end of the day, it's not the
central factor in life. But when you are
16 or 17 years old and your hormones are
raging,
that's all you can think of.
And that's why the movies are all geared
towards these young gullible people.
Everyone's been there.
Yeah?
So, you want people to buy a ticket and
you want them to be inflamed with ideas,
and that's why
these movies are typically geared
towards young people who are still awash
in hormones and they'll like
So,
pop culture obviously exaggerates
romance and all that.
Romance is important,
but it's not the central thing in life.
It's not like it's the it should be the
top priority for people in life.
Top priority in life it Life is a
balanced thing. There's a place for
everything.
Everything should be in in the right
place in the right proportions at the
same time.
Uh but
yeah.
Pop media will obviously exaggerate
things. Pop culture.
To make money. It's it's all about money
making money, right?
Amiroop Sarkar says, "Will Venezuela
intervention be a pushback against the
dedollarization in oil? Any idea how
much it how much it may impact oil deals
made in Chinese yuan?"
Of course, this is going to bolster
the US dollar, the strength of the US
dollar.
See, like I've said many times, why is
the US dollar the predominant currency
in the world?
It was it was
decided in 1944
in the Bretton Woods conference
to make the US dollar the world's
reserve currency.
At that time
the US dollar was pegged to the price of
gold.
Then Richard Nixon unpegged it from the
price of gold. It became a free flow
floating fiat currency. Just paper.
Then it was pegged to the price of
petroleum. So it became the petrodollar.
And the US enforced the petrodollar
status through its military might. Which
means that across the world if you
wanted to buy petroleum you could only
pay in US dollars.
And people tried to change that. Saddam
Hussein tried to change that. He was
taken out. Muammar Muammar Gaddafi tried
to change that. He was taken out.
Nicolas Maduro tried to do that. He has
been taken out.
So the petrodollar status the the
world's reserve currency status of the
US dollar is enforced through military
might.
Through through force.
And Venezuela accounts for about 20% of
the world's proven oil reserves. Now all
of that oil whenever it is sold in
whatever quantity
at whatever number of barrels per year,
it will all be sold in US dollars only
now.
So that strengthens the the uh reserve
currency status of the US dollar.
Right?
There will be no more Venezuelan oil
sold in Chinese yuan or anything else.
So yeah, it's it how will it impact oil
deals in made in China Chinese yuan?
Well, other oil from other countries
it may still perhaps on occasion be sold
in Chinese yuan. But this 20% no chance
now.
EKS Bagga says, "How come the US has
33-34% of global wealth with only 4%
global population while Russia with 75
trillion worth of resources has less
than one?"
Why is it so hard to imagine?
They have 4% of the global population,
but they have a huge continent that they
control. They control North America and
South America entirely now.
They project power across the entire
world.
The percentage of your population
doesn't matter. The amount of hard power
is is what matters, you see?
You may be
10,000 people
but if you control the entire world,
then you will have not 33% but the 100%
of the world's wealth.
Or you will control it directly or
indirectly.
So the amount of the percentage of the
global wealth you control is not
a factor of the
percentage of the world's population you
account for. It's a factor of how much
hard power you have.
Okay?
Uh so
that's what it is. It's a function of
your hard power. It it it depends on
your hard power. It doesn't depend on
your population. The UK
was a tiny little island. It still is.
But they controlled the entire world
essentially.
They do not even have 4% They don't they
not even have 1% of the world's
population.
And still they control the entire world
and had much of the wealth. So it is all
dependent on your hard power. It has
nothing to do with your population.
Aries Manticore says, "What kind of
short but continuous kinetic action
could Russia take to Kiev after
the recent assassination attempt
attempt?
What could China do now that Venezuela
is in the US control for its energy
interests?" Look, let's talk about China
first. Venezuela the past 5 years it has
exported
petroleum, right?
Between 65 to 80% of Venezuela's
petroleum exports went to China.
But when you look at China's oil
imports, Venezuela accounted for maybe
three or 4% only of China's oil imports.
So now that this is under US control,
China will not get the three 4% from
Venezuela. Which is fine. It doesn't
make too much of a difference to China.
Uh China imports 15 to 20% of its oil
from Saudi Arabia. It imports another 15
to 20% of its oil from Russia. Then you
have nations like Iraq, Angola, blah
blah blah blah blah from which it
exports the imports the rest of the oil.
So China has a bunch of nations from
which it imports oil and this
if Venezuelan oil no longer reaches
China, it will not make too much of a
difference to China.
Okay?
So energy interests China will be able
to look into it. If Iran is taken out,
that could be a big dent
to China's oil imports. We'll see about
that. Now what kind of short but
continuous short but continuous? If it
is short, how it is how is it
continuous? Short is the done.
But how can it be short and continuous
at the same time?
So what kind of kind of action could
Russia take to Kiev after the
recent assassination attack attempt? All
kinds of stuff. I will not go into it.
Russia has so many options.
If it wants, it can flatten Kiev
tomorrow morning.
It can entirely flatten Kiev tomorrow
morning if it wants.
Obviously it will not want to do that.
It's got all kinds of options.
Okay. Parthenon says, "UN replacement
migration paper says Russia needs
millions of immigrants. What is Russia
planning and what are the skilled people
they need right now ASAP?"
Um
Look, when when the UN writes about
Russia, we should be careful not to
believe it in its entirety. The UN is
controlled by the United States mainly.
And the US is anti-Russia, right? We
know that. The US regards Russia as an
adversary. So if the UN writes about
Russia, it's going to write things that
are going to be kind of biased. But
assuming that what the UN has written is
correct
that Russia needs millions of
immigrants.
What is Russia planning to do it about
this planning to do about this?
I suppose Russia could
import immigrants
from India.
So India has one thing in surplus which
is people.
So Russia could import skilled workers,
laborers from India on on a temporary
basis, not on a permanent basis. You
work for 5 years and go back that sort
of thing. Earn some money. Earn good
money.
Work here. Give us your your skills,
your labor and go back that sort of
thing. They could do.
So that's the Russia will be way more
will be way happier importing Indian
skilled labor compared to Chinese
skilled labor. Russia doesn't trust the
Chinese, okay? So one easy solution for
Russia is to import Indian skilled labor
on an ongoing basis. Maybe give 5-year
visas. After 5 years you go back.
In those 5 years you earn good money. So
it's win-win, right? You don't settle
down permanently, but you work for 5
years that sort of thing. So that's an
easy solution for Russia.
Easy. It can be implemented tomorrow
morning. Just
get on the phone with Mr. Modi, Mr.
Putin. Discuss this. Work out the
modalities. Can be implemented rapidly.
So it's not going to be a big problem
for Russia.
Okay? Indians are trustworthy.
Indians will not spy for the West.
Indians have skills. Indians are
plentiful. So
yeah. So that's that's an easy solution
for Russia.
Rajat says, "Can we do Venezuela in
Bangladesh for Yunus to put BNP in
power?" No.
India can't do it.
India is not powerful enough.
There is another nation which is
See, in the Indian subcontinent
there is another nation
other than India
which is more powerful than India.
That nation
is the United States.
The US is not physically in the Indian
subcontinent.
But the US has power projection
capabilities.
Not just military but economic.
And those capabilities are so powerful
that India can't do a thing in
Bangladesh right now.
If India tries something, India can
actually go tomorrow morning and change
the regime in Bangladesh.
They can do it.
But then the consequences will be
terrible.
The Americans will impose sanctions and
India's economy.
So come we can't do it.
Okay. Swapnil Mishra says, "Why did
Venezuela and Argentina
decline economically?"
So Argentina um
Argentina was never I mean
when was Argentina a great economy?
I think 100 years ago.
Maybe the 1910s, 1920s. At that time
Argentina was prosperous.
Buenos Aires was like the Paris of the
Americas and that sort of thing.
Um then what happened? I suppose
socialism happened in Argentina.
You had Peron.
Peron, right? What was his name?
Uh
Argentina Peron. He was a socialist.
Peron Juan Peron.
So, yeah.
1946 to 55. So, you had these people
Juan Peron was a socialist. If I
remember correctly, he was a
Peronism, right? Peronism
Juan Peron, social justice, economic
independence, etc.
Nationalism, inclusive
ethno-nationalism.
Is it socialistic, anti-communist,
progressive, conservative?
Female Peronist. Is it a social-
Yeah, national form of socialism. So,
you had people like Peron, etc., who
were more ideology-driven than than
driven by practical ideas.
And because of these things, Argentina
declined over time. The specifics, the
mechanics and statics of it, I won't be
able to explain in great detail, but
yeah, you had the wrong kind of wrong
leaders who took Argentina down the
wrong wrong path and ruined Argentina
slowly, gradually economically.
Venezuela. How did Venezuela decline
economically?
You know,
you will be you will be told that
Venezuela is in terrible economic shape
because of people like Maduro who have
ruined the economy. They don't know how
to run the economy. It's all socialism.
It's all communism. These commies have
ruined the country economically. The
truth the truth, my friends, is that
Venezuela's economy has been ruined by
American sanctions,
by Western sanctions.
When you impose a million sanctions on
the country and you cut the country's
country's economy off from the rest of
the world, you don't allow them to to
trade with the world, Venezuela in the
2010s
accounted for 10 to 12% of India's oil
imports.
In 2020, the Americans put a complete
halt to that.
And India was not allowed to import even
one drop of Venezuelan oil after that.
That's just one example of what was done
to Venezuela. Similarly, Venezuela would
have been exporting oil to so many other
countries. All of that was stopped.
And not just that, but all kinds of
other sanctions were were imposed on
Venezuela which crippled the Venezuelan
economy.
So, the major reason why Venezuela's
economy was crippled is because the
West, led by the US, imposed sanctions
on Venezuela.
That is the truth. It's not communism or
socialism that destroyed Venezuela's
economy. It is Western sanctions that
destroyed with Venezuela's economy.
Aries Mantecore says, "Why can't we
create a unique composite stealth
materials-based submarine along with a
stealth swarm of underwater drones? What
could its battlefield utility be? How
would it fare against regular subs?"
Look, you don't need stealth materials
in submarines. You can use regular
hulls, steel hulls. What you need is a
silent engine.
An engine can never be 100% silent,
okay? There's going to be some noise,
but you have to reduce the acoustic
signature as far as possible.
And you have to reduce the Well, is it
possible to reduce the magnetic
signature?
Because you have aircraft with magnetic
anomaly detectors,
those little tail protuberances
that
that scan the ocean for magnet magnetic
anomalies. So,
what you have to do, forget about that,
you have to make the sub as silent as
possible.
You don't need stealth materials.
You don't use radar to hunt for
submarines, right? Stealth materials and
stealth
taping technology is is relevant when it
comes to radars in the air.
So, it is relevant for aircraft. For
submarines, you can use regular steel
hulls, but you have to make it as silent
as possible.
Okay? So, you can use air-independent
propulsion. You can use advanced nuclear
reactors. You can use a
You can use propel propellers with with
which with uh
silent characteristics, etc. That's what
you do.
Okay?
So, yeah, that's that's what we need to
do. We need to work on the submarines.
We need to iteratively iteratively
produce better and better submarines.
We should uh look for these these
technologies like air-independent
propulsion and so on.
Um even if you're using diesel-electric
submarines, maybe we can
uh
incorporate, you know,
techniques and technologies that will
make it silent as or as silent as
possible.
That's what you do. Now, what about the
swarm of underwater drones? Yeah, we
should have those things. I think
underwater drones are underwater
submersible vehicles
are the the the the technology is being
worked on in India. Obviously, we will
not advertise that. We will not shout
from the rooftops, "We are doing this."
We'll keep quiet about that. But, I
suppose from whatever I've heard,
we are kind of
working on those things.
Kiran More says, "India just tested a
ramjet artillery shell." Let's look at
look into that. Okay, India ramjet
artillery shell. India ramjet
artillery. Let's see.
Um
India, in the first in the world, India
to develop deploy ramjet-powered shells
for 155 mm guns.
Let's see. Indian Army to be the first
to use ramjet-powered 155 mm artillery
shells.
Um
Uh first army to be the the the the the
the the the the the the the the the the
the the the the the
It will increase the range by 30 to 50%
while retaining the lethality.
Development of rockets with longer
ranges.
155 mm shells.
Ramjet shells. How does that work?
That's really interesting.
Ramjet-assisted 155 mm artillery shell.
Significant progress. This was January 2
20- This is yesterday.
Uh do do do do do do do
Okay, I'm sure the technology can be
done. So, that's interesting. A ramjet
powered or ramjet-assisted
artillery shell.
Interesting. A ramjet is essentially a
jet engine, a supersonic
No, not a supersonic jet a jet engine.
Yeah, then you have supersonic
combustion ramjets which are called
scramjets. Interesting. I will Well,
I'll follow that up.
Okay. Chintya Anand says, "Only Russia
and the US are powers that have full set
of mechanical replacements like steam
engines and warships in case of EMP
EMP attack."
You got to have they have these things.
The Americans have these ancient uh
ancient as in maybe Second World War era
warships
that are in mothballs, but these
warships can be redeployed
at reasonably short notice.
And these warships are powered by steam
engines and so on.
So, in case you have an electromagnetic
pulse kind of attack that that fries all
the modern electronics of advanced
modern warships, then you can bring out
those ancient warships and still
uh have a navy that you can deploy in
some numbers at least. And uh the
Russians also possibly have this.
What about India? I think India must
have scrapped all the old warships.
India has
probably scrapped all the old warships
and broken them down for scrap. So,
India won't have it.
Yeah.
Euler 01 says, "Is US playing the game
right or is it making blunders?" I think
India the US is playing the game right.
India is
the US
is using its hard power
to align all the pieces on the
chessboard in the right order, the order
that is most beneficial to it.
See, what's the what's the point of
having hard power if you don't use it?
Power exists to be used. If you don't
use it, power is useless, worthless.
So, the US has the power and it takes
the action
that is that needs to be taken. It
doesn't shy away from that.
So, it's taken Venezuela. We'll see
we'll see what it does next. The US is
playing the game right. It has put
Russia and China on the back foot.
They have been caught off guard. All
they have been able to do is make
statements and condemn what the US has
done. But, what action have they taken?
Nothing.
It shows how powerful the US is and how
relatively powerless, comparatively
powerless, Russia and China are. The US
is playing the game right as of as of
now.
Aries Mantecore says, "Trump said the US
military had a certain ability
to turn off VZ's power grid. What do you
think it is?" What is VZ? Venezuela's
power grid. Okay.
What do you think it is? Advanced weapon
they play? Just a kind of dangerous
weapon still hidden from public?
I think the US
government's
ability to turn off the military the
power grid of Venezuela,
it's not advanced technology.
It's cash.
Dollars.
Pay the right people, they'll switch it
off.
Why do you need super advanced
technology when you can just pay people
to do things?
You can just pay people. You can just
bribe people to do what you what you
want them to do.
As simple as that.
You have familia. You we give green card
to your familia, your wife, your
children. Bring them to the US. We give
them
good house, education. We give you a
million dollars in bank account. Switch
off the grid. Done.
Done deal.
ICMB says, "Just saying, James pays in
INR, so he lives in India." You see,
James is an advanced player.
He may pay in INR.
Maybe he has a credit card or a PayPal
account that can pay in INR.
You see?
You have to cover your tracks. Never
show people don't let people let people
know who they who you really are. Hide
your tracks, cover your tracks. I think
James plays the game really well.
Pratardana says early Christians debated
rebirth but church declared them
heretics and Christian philosophy
stopped evolving and is stuck with the
original sin of Adam.
Yes, it is said that the original
gospels or whatever the hell whatever
whatever that was, they did have the
concept of reincarnation. Maybe the Nag
Hammadi library
which is
an unedited
set of Christian texts. Maybe that has
the concept of reincarnation. See, there
was something called the Council of
Nicaea.
When was it held? I think
300 400 AD somewhere around that.
Council
of Nicaea.
325 AD was it? 325 AD.
Okay, Constantine I. And in this council
they they decided to
edit
the Christian texts and expunge any
mentions of reincarnation etc. from
Christian texts
in order to control the people early.
But what about the Nag Hammadi library?
Let's check check check that out.
Nag Hammadi
library.
Come on, library.
So, yeah, Gnostic gospels, right?
Discovered in 1945, second to fourth
centuries.
And these were
unedited documents that that Constantine
was not able to edit obviously.
And do we have reincarnation in that?
Let me see, does it have the concept of
reincarnation?
Did it have anything?
Yeah, it extensively discusses
reincarnation.
You see?
So, this was a very Hinduism-like
concept that you had in Christianity
before Constantine and his minions they
expunged it from the Christian gospels
from the Christian texts.
So,
original or early Christianity
it believed in the concept of
reincarnation or the trans-
transmigration of souls.
And once you turn your soul trans-
transmigrates, you forget the previous
births and so on.
That concept is very similar to what you
have in Hinduism and in the Dharmic
religions.
But then all of that was removed so that
people would believe that there's only
one life and everything goes to the
church. So, the church has complete
power and control over not just this
life of yours but even the afterlife,
whether you go to heaven or hell. If
there is reincarnation, there is no
heaven or hell, please understand that.
So, these artificial concepts were then
inserted into Christianity
during the as a consequence of the
Council of Nicaea.
UMXG lol haha says, "Why do we idol
worship while Abrahamics don't?"
Why do we idol worship while Abrahamics
don't?
Why do we do it Abra-
I think most cultures have made idols
of their gods.
Why did the Abrahamics say that it is
not good? I have no I look yeah, I'm not
really sure why the why the Abrahamics
See, the Abrahamic religions are newer
religions.
All the older religions had idols.
So, the question actually is why don't
they why did the Abrahamics decide that
idols are bad?
And then why did they proceed to break
idols all over the world
and desecrate idols all over the world?
So, I'm not sure. Look, I am not an
expert in Abrahamism.
In polytheism, polytheistic practices
were all were found all across the world
including in West Asia and all these
practices have idols.
So, when you conceive of some kind of
deity, you want some physical
representation of that that you can
focus your mind on. And that is a
representation of what you believe in.
And that makes sense.
So, why no idols? I have no idea. That
that
King Ritwik says, "Speak in Hindi in
Sir, speak Hindi in other channels but
not here. Why?" Well, this is an English
language channel.
I won't
I believe that my
what I have to say is kind of somewhat
importantish.
And I want this to be understood across
the world.
That's why I speak in English.
So, let me give you an example.
We know there is a bad situation
happening in Manipur right now.
Right?
Now, the people of Manipur
they discuss this stuff what's happening
on YouTube.
But they speak in the Manipuri language.
They have so much information about the
history and what's happening but they
discuss everything in the Manipuri
language. So, the rest of India has no
idea what's happening in Manipur even
though it's so important.
Now, if I start speaking Hindi
then only some Indians will be able to
understand what I'm saying. The rest of
the world will will have no idea what I
have to say.
I want
whatever I am saying to go out to the
entire world.
I think it's important it does.
Right now, the hegemonic language across
the world is the language of the
Anglo-Saxons.
It is what it is. So, I'm going to use
that language to put put forth
India's perspective, India's opinion in
front of the world. That's why I speak
in English
over here on my channel.
When I go to other channels, the hosts
may prefer to speak in Hindi because
their channels are primarily in Hindi.
In that case, I will respect that
channel's
language preference. I'll speak in
Hindi.
But it's not like I only speak in Hindi
in other channels.
There are many channels on which I will
go and speak in English.
So, that's the deal.
UMXG lol haha says, "What is the proof
of Persians being Vedic Indian Indians?"
See,
there are
you will not find this proof in your
textbooks. Your textbooks will not say
that Persians are of Indian origin, of
Vedic origin.
Your teachers will will say that this is
a conspiracy theory.
Okay? Progress is made
by questioning the official consensus
narrative.
Now, where is the proof? There is
plenty of circumstantial evidence.
And if you put all those threads
together, it becomes clear that the
Persians
were of Vedic origin. Let me give you
one example.
Okay.
Aryan invasion myth.
So,
if you go here,
this is just one piece of evidence. This
is not the only evidence by the way.
Uh
Where do we have it? See, look here.
See, these are the names, non-Hellenized
names of ancient Persian kings.
Achaemenish,
Aryaramna, Uvakhshatra, Kurush Vajraka,
Kambujiya, Vishtaspa, Darayavahush,
Khshayarsha, Artakhshatra.
These are the names of ancient Persian
kings from the Achaemenid dynasty,
clearly Sanskrit names. Now, another
one, okay?
Okay, Talagiri.
Talagiri 10 kings.
Okay, let's see here.
Battle of the 10 kings. So, we have the
names of the various clans that fought
and were defeated. The western opponents
of Sudas.
So, we have the Simyus, the Bhrigus, the
Druhyus, the Alinas, the Bhaktas,
the Vishanins, the Bhalanas,
etc. Who else do we have? More western
opponents, the the Bhishachin, the
Vishanin, Simyu, Dasa.
Parshu, Parshva.
You see the Parshva clan. They went
westwards.
They went westwards and they founded the
region of Persia. So, if you look at all
these pieces of evidence, you put them
together, it becomes very clear that the
Persians are descendants of one of the
clans, the Parshva clans, that was
defeated in the Battle of the 10 kings.
And you can see all the all the pieces
of evidence all line up.
But if you want one piece of proof, you
won't have it.
And none of this is accepted by your
mainstream darbari historians.
Okay? But if you have a mind that works
and if you can follow the strands of
logic,
then you can see the truth. The problem
is that the proof is very complex. There
are 50 different pieces of evidence from
different disciplines and domains. And
you have to tie all the threads in
together. It's very complex and most
people don't have the patience
to follow the strands together. You will
say, "Where is the proof?" You want one
piece of proof. If if I don't show it,
then you will say you are lying or you
are a you have no idea what you're
talking about. This is the problem.
Okay.
One more myth Indians believe in, sir,
please answer. Well, one myth Indians
believe in is that the Persians are a
foreigner foreign foreign clan, a
foreign country, no connection to India.
That's a myth most Indians believe. And
they'll say, "Where is the proof?" when
you claim that Persians are of Vedic
origin.
That's another myth, you see?
Stylin it says, "What was the culture in
Eastern Iraq India?" Well, sorry.
What was the culture in Eastern India
in parts like Bihar, Bengal at the times
of the Vedic ages, since this region was
beyond the borders of the core Vedic
lands where the adversaries?
Look, we have very little evidence from
the Vedic times. Whatever evidence we
have is from the text of the Vedic
times. The Vedas. The oldest obviously
is the Rigveda. And then you have
evidence from other texts like the
Mahabharata, Ramayana, etc. Um what was
the culture like in this Eastern India?
We don't quite know for sure.
The only text that survives is from the
oldest times is the Rigveda.
And whatever
is recorded in the in the Rigveda is
what we know of ancient India from from
that time.
Um so I'm not sure what the culture was
like. Obviously we had people all across
India.
But the Rigveda was mostly most likely
written closer to 6,000 BC than to 2,000
BC.
So if a text is written, let's say 5,000
BC, that's 7,000 years before today.
The world was a very different place.
The subcontinent was a very different
place at the time. Obviously you would
have people all across the place.
But what was the culture like in other
parts of
the subcontinent
not the core Vedic region, which is the
Ganga Yamuna Valley. I'm not sure.
Not not very sure. Obviously you're
right. You're saying that this region
was beyond the borders of the core Vedic
lands. Were these people adversaries?
Not necessarily not likely.
See, if you are living 1,000 km away
from the core Vedic lands,
you may never meet each other in your
lifetimes or in in five generations.
Because those days, unless you did the
Ashwamedha Yagna or something, nobody
will travel that far.
Unless you are going on pilgrimage or
whatever. So we are not quite sure.
We are not quite sure.
Uh when it comes to the Eastern lands
like Bengal for example or the Magadh
region, Bihar,
uh you could get some information from
archaeological research.
But very little archaeological research
has has been done. For example, in
Bengal, the oldest archaeological sites
are
what? Chandraketugarh,
which is about 2 and 1/2 thousand years
before today or something. So pretty
recent stuff.
For India, 2 and 1/2 thousand years is
pretty recent, right? Because we are
talking about what happened 7,000 years
ago.
So if we do proper archaeological work,
you will find archaeological evidence
and artifacts, which will paint a better
and richer picture of what life was like
in Eastern India.
As of now, the ASI is not
bothered to do these things. So we don't
quite know.
And textually, we only have the Rigveda,
which describes the Vedic lifestyle.
So don't have the answer right now,
sadly.
Aries Manticore says, "Minnesota's
forced
of Somalian migrants and the
billion-dollar scams they are currently
committing against US citizens
while the state is enabling them and the
federal government is strangely silent."
Minnesota's forced of Somalian migrants.
What does it mean?
We know there are Somalian Somalian
migrants
in Minnesota.
And apparently they are billion-dollar
scams.
And obviously the scams victimize the
legal citizens of the US, of course.
And the state of Minnesota is enabling
them. Yes, yes.
The federal government is strangely
silent. I'm
I'm not sure the federal government is
entirely silent. They are not entirely
silent on social media, but they are not
really taking any action against
uh what's happening.
Which is strange.
The West has weaponized migration
against itself. Right? The West has
chosen has decided at some point in
time, we going to
import people from certain parts of the
world.
People from certain regions of the world
who who have certain cultures only.
We going to hate on the Indians and the
Hindus.
But we going to bring in people from
certain parts of Africa and who have
certain specific religions.
And we going to empower them.
I don't know what the what the deal is.
But clearly the West seems to be in the
process of digging its own grave.
So yeah, okay. Do it.
What am who am I to say anything?
Teja Reddy says, "Key differences Bay of
Bengal versus Arabian Sea."
So the Bay of Bengal is
is the Kalinga Mahasagar.
The Arabian Sea is actually the Sea of
Saurashtra.
That's two key differences. That's one
key difference already.
Sea of Saurashtra, Kalinga Sagar,
Kalinga Mahasagar, whatever. Secondly,
the Sea of Saurashtra is in the west
west coast of India.
And the Kalinga Sagar is on the east
coast of India. That's another key
difference.
Beyond that, I don't know.
I mean, look at the map here.
KEP, no question, but okay. Thank you
very much, sir. KEP, merci beaucoup.
Aries Manticore says, "Christianity only
evolved into multiple variants in the US
but remain only three in Europe. It
seems interesting. Why so? Interesting.
So in Europe you have Protestantism,
you have Catholicism,
and you have the Orthodox Church,
which the Orthodox Christianity, which
you will find in the Balkan region in
Greece,
also in in in in Russia. In Russia you
have Orthodox Christianity, yes?
In Greece also. Bulgaria,
possibly Bulgaria also. So the Balkan
region in Russia, that's where you have
Orthodox Christianity.
You have Protestantism in
Germany, in England, etc. Other parts of
Europe. France also, the the the
Huguenots, etc. And you have
Catholicism. Three variants of
Christianity. In the US, you have the
Baptists, the Anabaptists, and God knows
what. Why is it so? I'm not really sure.
It's interesting for sure.
But why has it
evolved in this manner very differently
in the US?
I haven't studied this thus far.
So I can't really say, but it's
interesting for sure.
It probably has something to do with the
special characteristics of the US as a
nation, which is very different from the
European nations, even though it's
composed of European invaders.
But they found this entire gigantic vast
continent
to run rampage in, and they evolved very
differently from the rest of the of the
Europeans, and maybe that gave rise to
different branches of Christianity.
But I haven't studied this in detail. So
can't say for sure.
UMXG Lol haha says, "Pasta is actually
Indian. Why call it Italian?"
How so? How is pasta
How is pasta Indian? Is pizza also
Pasta, its origins are in China.
There was no pasta in in in in Italy
before Marco Polo came back from China.
And Marco Polo brought noodles from
China, and he introduced those in Italy.
And the Italians then took it forward
and made it their own thing, and they
called it pasta. So pasta is Italian,
okay? It's not Indian.
KEP says, "Why do people say it's Indian
nationalism when Indians claim it, but
when Europeans claim it, people just
accept it as fact?" Because the world is
Eurocentric. The past 500 years, the
Europeans have ruled the world.
And they have put forth their narrative
and their claims as the gospel truth.
And if anyone challenges that, that is
portrayed as as as nationalism or
propaganda or conspiracy conspiracy
theories.
And
because of the European predominance
over the past five centuries, even
non-European people
have been brainwashed into believing
that everything the European says is
right and everything anyone else says is
wrong. So many Indians are also like
that, right? Mentally colonized. If an
Indian person says something, "Nah, nah,
must be wrong." If if a white person
says the same thing, "Yes, obviously
it's true."
Right?
And in India we have this this this
this practice
that if an Indian person does some great
achievement, we will ignore it. But if
that Indian person gets an award from
the West,
then the Indian government will give a
Padma Shri or something to the to the
Indian person. But only after they get
an award from the West.
So that's an issue with Indians, right?
Mental colonization, inferiority
complex, mental
slave mentality
that permeates all levels of Indian
society, the bottom to top.
Rajat says, "Will we ever know what
happened before
10 raised to minus 32 seconds?"
Will we ever know?
Well, we can kind of try and deduce
theorize what may have happened based on
indirect
evidence.
But it's all going to be theories,
right?
We may never know for sure what happened
before 10 raised to minus 32 seconds.
Uh
it's essentially the onset of inflation,
isn't it?
When does inflation start? The
inflationary epoch starts in the very
early universe.
And before that we have the
pre-inflationary universe, which is the
very early universe, which is
fascinating, but we have absolutely next
to no next to no idea about it.
So we may never See, to know something
to actually know something, you need
data.
Now, where do we find data about
what the universe was like
before 10 raised to minus 32 seconds?
We should have evidence right here.
Because this this region of space right
here between my my palms,
this was
once part of the very early universe
before minus 10 raised to 32 seconds.
But do I see any evidence here? So, it
may be perhaps impossible to know what
happened before that.
But the human mind is ingenious. You
come up with the right theories and you
can
if the theories make sense
mathematically, if they can
well, resolve
major major intractable intractable
issues such as reconciling the very
small with the very large, for example,
which is quantum gravity, then maybe you
may be able to have better insights
about what the world was like before the
inflationary epoch.
Um
UMXGLOLHAS says
LazyGamer says, "Sir is an occasional
drinker."
Who is LazyGamer and how does LazyGamer
know what do I what do I do in life?
Uh Harsh Vardhan Johar, thank you very
much, Harsh Vardhan ji. Thank you.
Sh- Sushant Gurjar says, "When Aryan
kingdoms suddenly emerged deeper in
Asia,
how did Indians who had lived for so
many thousands of years in India
acclimatize to the different elevation
and climate there?"
You see,
we say that Aryan kingdoms suddenly
emerged, let's say,
deeper in Asia.
Maybe
Anatolia, for example, around 2000 BC
1600 BC.
So, we imagine
that
10,000 Indians
boarded
Boeing five Boeing planes, took a flight
from New Delhi,
and landed in Anatolia,
and they came out of the plane and
suddenly they were in a very different
climate. It was so cold and they
couldn't acclimatize. That's what we
imagine. But what actually happened
is Indians
traveled
either on foot or by horse slowly
westwards
over years, perhaps decades, perhaps a
couple of centuries.
And when you travel slowly,
you don't even realize that you have
acclimatized.
That's how it actually works in the real
world.
They do not go by aircraft or
helicopter.
So, if you're sitting in, let's say,
Chennai, or you're sitting in Bangalore,
and you take a flight,
and 4 hours later you are in Leh,
and you come out of the aircraft, you're
suddenly met with the shock.
Very high altitude, very thin
atmosphere,
and very cold temperature.
That's where you get a climate shock.
But if you walk from Bangalore all the
way to Leh,
it will take you maybe a few months.
By the time you reach Leh, you were
acclimatized already. See the
difference? All right.
Karan says, "I never claimed it was
Arabic.
It was Persian and Timurid, but much
built much earlier."
You're talking about what?
You're talking about the Taj Mahal dome
thing?
Okay, you are saying the Indian claim is
weakened and okay, all right, all right,
sir. Good good luck.
AriesManticore says, "I saw video on the
Romani people by European.
It painted them terribly, and the
comment section was even worse. I don't
get it. What's going on? Why are they
doing this to them? It's pure and simple
racism.
They don't like people who have
non-white skin.
The Romani people, they are not white.
They have darker skin.
Maybe dark skin like regular Indians or
light brown skin.
And their facial features are Indian.
They the Europeans
I'm not saying all of them are racist,
but it's a pretty racist society. It's
It's a pretty racist set of societies.
It's all to do with racism.
If the same Romani people had white
skin, they would not be treated the same
way. Let me give you an example of how a
Romani person was treated in Europe. Let
me give you one example. You may not
have heard of it. Okay, I'm going to go
to Google.
I'm going to search for Johann
Trollmann.
Johann Trollmann.
This person, Johann Trollmann,
was a German boxer of Romani origin.
Okay?
Look at him here. He's here with the
other German boxers. You can see his
skin color is darker.
He's the tallest of the lot.
Okay, a Romani Indian origin boxer.
You can see his skin color is different.
He's the tallest of the lot. He was the
best boxer in Germany in his weight
class.
But unfortunately,
he was born in 1907, and he lived his
his the prime of his career was during
the time of the Third Reich.
Okay?
So, Johann Trollmann.
He was different from the Germans. His
boxing style was different. The German
boxing style was stand and fight and
take the punches.
Johann Trollmann had this very light
mobile style of boxing. He was very
light on his feet. He moved around a
lot.
He would evade punches. He would not
stand and take punches.
And he became the German boxing
champion.
And then
he was awarded the championship, but
then he was disqualified
under some pretext.
And
I think he was made to fight another
match and in as a protest, he came to
fight
after covering himself in in wheat flour
because he was dark-skinned. So, he
covered himself in wheat flour to make
himself white and said, "Okay, now am I
German enough? Can I fight now?" That
sort of thing.
Eventually, he was sent to to a
concentration camp
because he was of Romani origin. He was
not German
despite being a German citizen. And I I
think he was murdered there.
He was the greatest boxer in Germany.
So, why was he treated like this?
Because of the color of his skin.
There's so many examples of this. Okay?
So, even today, this racism is alive and
well in Europe.
Ayush says, "Sorry if I'm wrong, but
many of the chief architects of Mughal
mosques were designed by Persian
architects. As example, Humayun's Tomb
was
designed by Mir Sayyid Ali and Abd
al-Samad
who introduced double dome to India from
Persia."
Okay, sir.
I mean, what's the argument? What are
you trying to prove here?
You're trying to prove that I'm wrong
about something.
In a previous episode,
I had said that Okay, let me try and get
to the bottom of what you're trying to
argue here, which is okay.
I am perfectly happy
to accept
an argument in which I am wrong if you
can
demonstrate that I'm actually wrong.
Now, let me see
which one was it. Okay,
what I'm doing is I'm I'm looking at my
channel. I put out these clips, right?
So,
uh let's see. Let's see together.
There is something about Taj Mahal or
something.
Where is it? Where is it? Come on.
Okay, Taj Mahal isn't Islamic
architecture. Here is proof. Okay, so
that was the thing, right? Whether the
Taj Mahal is Islamic architecture or
not.
So, I have said it is not Islamic
architecture.
It is Indian and Persian architecture.
And these
these this this style of this this
tradition of having this this these
domes,
it
came mainly from India.
And it also existed in the Byzantine
Empire, etc.
And Ayush is saying it is Persian and
and and and Turkic.
Persian genius.
They introduced double domes to India
from Persia.
So, the problem is
we had incredible temples in northern
India, etc., before 1000 AD. All those
were destroyed.
You had tremendous domed structures.
All of those were destroyed. So, we
don't have evidence in modern India now.
In southern southern India, you have the
temple style, which is in a different
shape, which emulates Mount Meru, Mount
Kailash.
So, I can't prove
because of the lack of evidence, because
of the destruction, that you had domed
structures in India before 1000 AD.
Can you prove that you had domed
structures
like this in Persia before 1000 AD? Or
before Yeah, before 1000 AD.
I don't think you can.
My point is this is not Islamic
architecture.
And I think I've made my point there.
So, if you're arguing about something
else, my argument is that this is not
Islamic architecture. I showed you on
the screen.
You are now making a different argument
about it is Persian or it is Turkic,
something else. I have said it is not
Islamic architecture, and I stand by my
point. You want to argue about something
else? Well, you can keep arguing. It's
fine. It's fine. But that is not my
argument. See, when I make one point,
and then you argue about something else,
you're arguing about a different topic.
Okay.
Anyway, my point is Ayush, I am not
upset with you. I'm not annoyed with
you. Uh it's it's difficult to have a
conversation when you're not
face-to-face.
And it often seems like you're talking
to each other at cross purposes. So I'm
not upset or annoyed with you, but I was
making a different point there.
All right? Okay.
Okay.
Arnab Jindal says one thing about the
Holocaust always seemed odd that no one
calls the Holocaust a Christian genocide
of the Jews. Like it isn't like isn't it
the continuation of the pogroms of Jews
conducted by European for Europeans for
almost 1,000 years until that point.
Yeah.
Isn't it odd?
It is of course
a continuation of the pogroms
conducted by Europeans
against Jews
for 2,000 years.
2,000 years.
No question about it.
But it's not called a Christian
genocide.
Yeah?
Isn't it odd?
They will absolve themselves of all the
sins. That's what they do.
Vamsi says is de-dollarization really
happening? Will the recent authoritative
action by Trump catalyze
de-dollarization or will it slow down
out of fear? How many years till the US
power diminishes like Britain's?
Is de-dollarization really happening?
It's not.
There are some very
very very very intelligent people who
claim de-dollarization is the only thing
in the world.
There are nations that seek to have
an alternative world order
in which the US dollar is not the
primary currency.
Maybe a basket of currencies or
something. China doesn't China seeks to
have a world that doesn't depend on the
dollar. So does Russia.
India also it will be beneficial for us
if the world is no longer
dependent only on the US dollar if the
US dollar is not the hegemonic currency
anymore.
But are we there?
Or is the process happening?
The process to some extent seemed to be
happening.
But then now we have Venezuela.
20% see
the US dollar is primarily
hegemonic because if you want to
purchase oil you have to purchase it in
US dollars. The Russians and the Chinese
have been dealing in yuan etc.
But the majority of the world still
purchases oil in US dollars.
Now Venezuela which accounts for 20% of
the world's proven oil resources now
all of its oil will be traded only in
dollars.
So this makes the dollar stronger.
This actually
reverses to some extent whatever little
trend there was towards so-called
de-dollarization.
So
de-dollarization is not happening.
Eventually someday
the dollar will no longer be the
hegemonic and currency in the reserve
currency.
But that day is not soon.
Right now India is not even talking
about moving beyond the US dollar. Only
China and Russia are openly speaking
about this.
No other countries no other country is
talking about this.
Or taking any actions. You take action
you're going to be squashed by the
Americans like what they did to
Venezuela. Before that
to Muammar Gaddafi before that to Saddam
Hussein. Whoever dares
to
even discuss
threatening the hegemony of the US
dollar you know what happens to them.
So it's only Russia and China that have
the
wherewithal to even speak about this. No
one else can do it. So it's not
happening right now.
Critical thinker Yati says apparently
the peace prize was given to a
puppet to make him famous locally then
to give him power after invasion.
Next peace prize from Cuba or Iran or to
Indian puppet.
Maybe somebody from India.
Um look for in Iran I suppose if there
is an invasion of Iran and a regime
change then they will make the
the son of the Shah
the son of Mohammad Reza Pahlavi they'll
make him the puppet king of Iran or
puppet Shah of Iran.
Uh he doesn't need a Nobel Peace Prize
because he's not really done anything
much.
Uh there's this lady from Venezuela what
is her name? Whatever her name is. So
this Venezuelan lady
her name is Maria Machado right? Maria
Machado. She was given the peace prize
and she has been openly speaking about
selling off the country piece by piece
to the Americans. The lady has no shame.
Yeah? But she's not going to be the the
president.
It's not going to work out for her. So
all of this in vain for her sadly.
Uh so what do you So the Nobel Peace
Prize has no legitimacy actually.
It is something that is used to to to to
create the conditions for regime change.
It is used to create the consent for
regime change.
Um
Cuba is not that important. The US
doesn't care about invading Cuba. What's
the point? There's no resources in Cuba.
Yeah. So let let Cuba be they'll say.
Maybe the next peace prize could be from
Iran
if you want to give it to the Shah and
then position him him as the next Shah
or the son of the Shah or maybe somebody
from India some aspiring Zelensky from
India possibly.
That could be on the cards.
UMXG lol haha says is it true that gangs
really ran cities like Karachi? I don't
know about Karachi. I I have not studied
Karachi.
I have no idea. That's what they've
shown in the movie right Durandar.
But I am not aware of
what the actual history is like has been
like in Karachi. Maybe it was but I
don't know.
Right.
Um Godliness says can you explore and
explain the quality of Chinese military
equipment? It seems their air defense
fails every time they whether it's
Pakistan or Venezuela.
Look exploring right now will take a few
hours. You can't explore in two three
minutes.
So if I were to explore and study and
analyze the quality of Chinese military
equipment I would have to go through
lots of sources do a lot of deep digging
look at case studies use studies look at
instances where Chinese equipment has
been used in actual combat or battle
like situations
actual action and see which equipment
was used what whether it was export
versions what whether it was older
versions new versions what was the
performance like it is a long long long
thing to study.
And I haven't done this.
So I can't really say I mean
we know that Chinese radars were used by
the Pakistanis during operation Sundoor
and those radars did not really work the
radars were taken out.
Um
the air defense systems that the
Pakistanis had of Chinese origin those
did not work.
Uh Chinese missiles that were the
Pakistanis fired were retrieved
essentially intact by India. So they did
not hit the targets they did not
explode.
So looks like the export versions of the
Chinese equipment whichever was exported
to Pakistan
has performed very badly.
But there's always a difference between
export versions and the versions that
the country actually uses.
So if China manufactures a piece of
equipment it's going to manufacture
a lower quality version of that and that
will be the export version that will not
have all
the
the cutting edge characteristics that
the main piece of equipment will have.
If you export it you're going to keep
out all the best
best best best uh
characteristics or or features
so that if that piece of equipment that
you've sold to a third country if it
falls into the hands of your adversaries
they should not be able to reverse
engineer
your cutting edge technology and they
should not be able to
figure out
how advanced your technology is. So
that's why you always export inferior
versions of equipment.
And that obviously will not perform the
way your actual original equipment
performs.
So based on the performance of the
export versions that Pakistan had you
can't really judge the quality of the
actual Chinese equipment. But what we
can say for sure about Chinese military
equipment is that it is not battle
tested.
It's not battle tested.
India's stuff is battle tested. China
not quite so.
So can't really say how well or badly it
will perform.
But Clevin says why can't the US do an
inside job in Russia or China?
See to do an inside job you need a few
traitors.
Which means you need to cultivate assets
within the higher echelons of a nation.
For China the US to do an inside job it
will have to cultivate people in the
high levels
high ranks of the Chinese Communist
Party.
For Russia they will have to cultivate
people high up in the inner circle of
Vladimir Putin.
In the 2010s
the Chinese security agency internal
security agency the MSS
that is the Chinese version of the FBI.
The MSS identified
and arrested between 10 to 20
American assets in China within the
Chinese Communist Party.
The Chinese government
the MSS it arrested
between 10 and 20
Chinese
individuals who were spying on behalf of
the US.
Uh if you do not believe me
let me see if I can find the evidence of
that and show it to you.
Let me see New York
Times.
Let me give you a second. Let me show
you 1 second.
Okay, so
um
I'm making a rather
remarkable claim here.
So,
check this out.
This article is obviously behind a
paywall. It's the New York Times. What's
the title? Killing CIA informants, China
crippled US spying operations.
Let me refresh this, okay?
It's going to go behind a paywall, so it
won't it won't work. And the New York
Times is behind a paywall and I'm not
I'm not subscribed to that.
So,
but you saw the title.
If you have access to the article, do
read it.
So,
the Chinese
identified and arrested between 10 to 20
or maybe more
American assets within the Chinese
Communist Party.
And these were executed.
They're killed.
So, now it is
so
as a consequence,
if they did a proper purge of the
American spies, the traitors who were
working for for America,
then the US doesn't have
sufficient people within China to do an
inside job.
And I suppose something similar would
have happened within Russia.
But that may not be publicized.
So, the US tries,
but the Chinese caught them all, at
least caught a few.
Now, what about India? You may ask. I
have no idea.
Mary Cain, hi Mary.
Mary says Google AI calls ancient Indian
Indian temples temple universities. Were
temples material science engineering
projects?
So, temples were an integral part of
India's ancient education system.
Uh
So, temples were not merely places where
people went for worship,
for prayers, for spiritual needs.
Temples were schools.
So, there was a time in India before
before 1000 AD when you had temples all
across India, across the length and
breadth of India. Every time every town,
every village
every neighborhood would have a temple.
Usually small temples with one person,
you know, one one one priest who would
be in charge of the temple, the priest's
family.
And
that local locality temple was where you
would send your little kids to study.
And they would be taught basic stuff,
you know,
basic writing and reading skills,
arithmetic, grammar, that sort of thing.
Eventually,
after a certain age, you would send them
to a larger temple to get better
education, higher education. I mean,
higher than what they were receiving.
So, it's like, you know,
kindergarten level education, then you
have primary level education and so on.
So, all of this education was imparted
in temples.
And eventually, if you wanted higher
education, you would go to places called
viharas and mahaviharas,
which were like colleges, and eventually
you would send people to universities,
vishwavidalayas.
So, the entire education system was
centered around temples.
And you had some great temples which
would also function as universities.
So, you had a number of really really
great magnificent temples all across
northern and southern India, across
India. Most of these have been destroyed
now. Most of the temples in northern and
western India, even eastern India have
been destroyed. The only great temples
that still stand are in southern India
today. And of course, you have some
great temples outside of India like uh
Prambanan in Indonesia, like
like like like Angkor Wat in uh
Cambodia, etc. These were also part of
the same overall civilizational
education
complex.
So, uh
And then you had uh
you had universities that were not
temples also. You had universities like
Takshashila, like Nalanda, like
Odantapuri, like Vikramashila,
Sharada Peeth, and so on and so on. Lots
and lots which were not temples where
you would get very specialized education
in a multitude of fields.
Um
And then you had the structure of Indian
society that was divided into
clans called jatis.
And each jati was organized along
um
occupational lines.
So, if you were
the family of goldsmiths, you would be
part of the jati of goldsmith in your
region, which was one community that
married among each other. So, that the
trade secrets never went out.
And that's where that way you had
innumerable jatis across the country.
So, once your kids got the basic
education, then you would pull them out
of school and then then your family or
your your guild would impart them
specialized
technical education related to your
occupation. So, that's how it was done
in India. It was a very
well-oiled system, a system that had
evolved over millennia.
And today it's entirely gone. It was
wiped out in the
19th century by the British occupiers.
So, that's kind of that's kind of how
the system was organized. Some of the
temples were indeed universities, but
many universities were not temples. But
all temples were educational
institutions. It was a pretty organic
bottom-up kind of
organic
structure. All these temples and
institutions were interlinked.
If you wanted to send a student to a
great university,
your local temple
educator would I suppose give a letter
of recommendation.
And the student would go. And that would
be enough to get
uh
um entry.
I'm sure there would be an entrance exam
and all. So, it was a pretty it was a
very interesting system, and sadly it's
gone.
Firefly says, "Any historical mystery
that intrigues you?"
Well, this
historical mystery that intrigues me the
most is the
truth about the origin of the Indian
people, the ancient history of India.
What was like during What was life
during the like during the Vedic age?
What are the true names of the great
cities that we have across the Saraswati
Sindhu region?
The place that we call Mohenjo-Daro. The
place that we call
Harappa. What were the original names?
5,000 years ago they were not called
Mohenjo-Daro and Harappa, right?
They had some actual original names that
have been lost in time.
What about Rakhigarhi? What about
Kalibangan? What about Birhana? What are
the original names of these great
cities?
We've lost all of these. These are
massive historical mysteries.
These do intrigue me.
Uh Kumar Kanishka says, "US capturing
Maduro and taking up Venezuela's oil for
themselves. Is this some sort of
neocolonization which we just witnessed
in the name of freedom and democracy?"
This is
the Monroe Doctrine
in action along with the Trump corollary
to the Monroe Doctrine.
So, and this is neo-imperialism, plain
and simple.
That's That's the naked reality of the
world. That's That's the way the world
has always been. So, what is this Monroe
Doctrine?
The Monroe Doctrine was a foreign policy
formulated by the United States in 1823.
This doctrine
the Monroe Doctrine, it declared
that the Americas
were closed henceforth to any new
European colonization attempts.
Okay? And any European interference in
the Western Hemisphere in the Americas
would be treated henceforth by the US as
a hostile act against the United States.
That was the Monroe Doctrine. It had to
be enforced obviously
by force, by hard power.
Once you put out this statement, you
have to enforce it only through hard
power.
So, that was 1823. So,
the Monroe Doctrine has now been
revived.
And
something called the Trump corollary has
been added to it. What is this Trump
corollary? It's a
new reinterpretation
of the Monroe Doctrine. It It says that
the US now has the right to police the
Western Hemisphere. The US is going to
be the supercop in the Western
Hemisphere.
And they're going to ensure that no
extraterritorial
extraregional powers
can have any influence in the region.
And even regional actors
such as drug cartels, etc., will no
longer be allowed to operate. We're
going to preserve US dominance and
hegemony in the region, and we will
We will be the security provider in the
region. That is the Trump corollary to
the Monroe Doctrine.
And
any nation that stands against the US,
they'll be dealt with in the most in the
harshest of ways. And this is the the
Monroe Doctrine and the Trump corollary
in action, what we just saw yesterday in
Venezuela. That's the deal. It is pure
and simple neo-imperialism.
But there's nothing wrong or right about
it.
That's the way the world has always
operated. And now we are seeing the
truth about We are seeing it in real
life.
It is what it is.
Okay. Biju Saikia says, "What's the
difference between an artificial and a
genuine nation?
You once called Germany an artificial
nation created by Bismarck.
I think one day German states were bound
to get united." Well, the German
principalities were not united for 2,000
years.
The Romans
uh coined the term Germania Magna.
That's where the word Germany comes
from.
They coined this term 2,000 years ago.
When the Romans were interested in
colonizing, you know, and and
administering Germania Magna, right?
And they encountered a major setback in
10 AD.
The Battle of Teutoburg Forest, when the
Germanic tribes united under
Arminius,
Herman the German,
and they routed three Roman legions.
So, why didn't the German people unite
then?
In 10 AD, 1,000 2,015 years ago,
they did not unite.
They all spoke Germanic languages.
So, from that day
until 1871, Germany never united. That's
2,000 years, roughly.
So, how can you say that one day German
states were bound to be united?
They would never have united unless
somebody with the extraordinary
force of character and will, someone
like Otto von Bismarck,
only someone like him could make this
happen.
So, he artificially united
a naturally disunited region.
Do you understand? It was a naturally,
organically disunited region. It had
never
ever been united in the form of in shape
of one kingdom or empire or nation.
It was always part of some empire or
kingdom,
but never a German empire or kingdom.
And that's why I say it's an artificial
nation.
In the case of India, it's organically
one unified thing.
It has on on multiple occasions been
united under under one single empire.
And it's always been one civilization.
So, that's the difference between India
and Germany.
So, what's the difference between an
artificial and a genuine nation? When
you create a territory that organically
doesn't
doesn't exist as as a united whole,
that's an artificial nation. Pakistan.
Has a nation called Pakistan ever
existed?
I mean, the region has always existed.
It's it's a geographical region.
But has any kingdom or empire ever taken
that shape and form with that culture
and religion? No.
It's entirely artificial.
It took external forces to do this.
So, that's that's an artificial nation.
A genuine nation is something that has
always existed in some some shape of
form. Maybe formally it was a kingdom or
an empire, but now it's a nation-state.
So, that's a genuine thing.
Okay, Sankarachiluguri says, "Scientific
works, mathematics, physics, medicine
were in Sanskrit in ancient India. No
matter what Prakrit language at home,
what Prakrit language at home, why
abandoned it after even after
independence?"
Uh what is the question?
You had scientific works, mathematics,
physics, medicine, etc. in Sanskrit.
No question about it. We have the texts.
We have the texts, mathematical texts,
astronomical observations, uh
physical laws.
You have pharmacology, you have
toxicology, you have botany, you have
zoology. You have all kinds of stuff.
We had that in ancient India. No
question about it.
Why abandoned it even after
independence? You see, this was not
abandoned. This the the line of inquiry
the lines of inquiry were destroyed.
These traditions
of investigation and inquiry and
research,
these were millennia-old traditions.
These were carried on continuously for
thousands of years
until about 1,000 AD,
when
the lineages were destroyed.
All the universities were destroyed
physically, the libraries were burned
physically,
and the scholars were beheaded
in the tens of thousands.
So, there was no one left
to carry on the work.
When the texts are destroyed, and the
persons who can transmit the texts and
explain the texts to students,
so that you can transmit the tradition
and carry it forward, those people were
killed off.
Then all research, all activity ended
around 1,000 AD.
Today we rediscover the texts, but they
are 1,000 years old.
The research stopped 1,000 years ago.
But in Europe and other places, the
research continued.
So, now these ancient texts are
obsolete.
They were the most advanced texts in
1,000 AD.
No other culture, civilization had that
amount of advancement
in these fields in 1,000 AD.
But for 2025, they are obsolete.
And from 1,000 AD to 2025, that's 1,025
years, there's been no research.
Do you understand what happened? That's
what happened.
So, it wasn't abandoned.
It was destroyed.
It's not like Indians decided, "You know
what? Today from today onwards, we will
not do research. We will just sit down
and relax.
We are done." It's not like that. That's
not what happened.
We did not abandon it.
It was destroyed. The tradition was
destroyed.
After independence, you know, we had
these mediocre leaders and secular
governments who hated everything Indian.
That's why it was never taken
again.
Kumar Kanishka says, "What can be the
reason we still lack in making
commercial passenger jet planes which is
from India? Lack of vision or just us
being complacent?" Indians, you give
them the opportunity, they will do
everything.
There are Indians who want to achieve
the greatest thing in the world. Indians
who want to go to space. Indians who
want to build jet engines. Indians who
want to build rocket engines. Indians
want to do everything.
The opportunities don't exist. The
funding doesn't exist. If the funding
exists, there's too much red tape,
there's too much corruption, there's too
much non-ease of doing business.
There's too many rules, regulations, red
tape, whatnot.
That's why no one's ever able to do
anything in India.
And what about DRDO, etc.? What what
what shall I say about DRDO?
There's no ambition at the highest
levels in government.
Why is ISRO
in a coma?
How many rocket launches in 2025? Four?
Five? What?
SpaceX launches double that every week.
I'm not sure it's double that. Maybe
SpaceX, how many launches last year?
200? 250? I don't know.
Way more than ISRO. I mean, there's no
comparison.
What about We have never even tried to
create a
to to to develop a passenger jet plane
in India. We've never even tried to do
that.
If individual entrepreneurs had the
idea, they never had the funding, they
never they were never allowed to do it.
And the government never had any
interest in it.
Now we are tying up with Sukhoi for the
Sukhoi Superjet 100 or whatever, which
is a good
place to start off.
So, we can code co- co-develop It's not
co-developing development. We're going
to manufacture it in India.
And hopefully,
see, the Chinese are so ambitious. They
are
They've already developed
a passenger plane. They are developing
reusable rocket engines. They are
developing They're trying to emulate
everything the Americans are doing right
now.
We are trying to emulate what the West
has done 30 years ago.
We are always 20, 30, 40 years behind
the world. It's a lack of ambition and
vision
Yeah, that that we are facing.
Godliness says, "It seems the quality
and training of the Russian forces are
not of good standards. US military
operations in Venezuela or Indian
operations in Dubai were of much better
quality. Why and how is Russia suffering
from this problem?" I disagree.
You were saying because Ukraine is a
slow war. Ukraine is a frozen conflict.
Because Ukraine
nothing is happening because Russia has
not overwhelmed Ukraine because Russia
has not won the Ukraine war so far,
that's why you're saying that the
training is not good and so on.
Slow war, frozen conflict, war of
attrition, slow grind. Russia is not
able to capture Kyiv. Russia is not able
to dislodge Zelenskyy. That's what
you're saying.
And that's why training is not good,
uh quality of the material is not good.
Look, this is all Western propaganda.
Russia is deliberately employing this
slow war strategy, the war of attrition
strategy, because it is depleting
Western resources. It is depleting the
Western will to fight.
It is actually bolstering Russia's
military-industrial complex.
Russia's economy is doing well.
Um and Russia has always believed in
quantity over quality. Quality should be
decent, but quantity is what matters.
I think that makes a tremendous amount
of sense. The Americans have extremely
complicated, sophisticated, high-quality
equipment.
Mhm?
Naval ships, the Zumwalt-class
destroyers and all.
But one destroyer will cost 2,000 two
two two billion dollars.
For that amount of money, the Chinese
will put out 20 ships which will
overwhelm the destroyer.
So, let's not fall for propaganda. I
don't agree with this.
Kalyan says,
"Okay, Kalyan also wants to disagree
with me." All right, mate. Thank you
very much for your perspective. Thank
you, sir.
Thank you for educating me. I am very
very honored, sir. Thank you.
Pratham Soni says, "Habits to develop
this year to raise our standards."
It depends depends on you.
What you want to do in life.
I would say one habit you should have is
to eat clean.
Eat food that you have cooked yourself
or somebody in your family has cooked.
Don't order from outside. That's one
habit. Secondly, um don't eat too much
obviously and don't eat too little also.
Secondly, exercise every day.
Third, spend some time reading, writing
every day. It depends, look, it's not
necessary that everybody has to do these
things.
I would say that you should read at
least half an hour every day.
You should write at least half an hour
every day.
But maybe you are in a field or in in a
domain that where you don't need any of
this. So, I can't really say.
But you have to take care of your body,
you have to take care of your mind, you
have to spend time outdoors, you have to
get sunlight, you have to
be strong physically, mentally.
And whatever field you're in, you have
to get better at that progressively,
iteratively.
Yeah.
Aman says,
"Can you please hint ways of real
information gathering?"
Well,
about what? About finance, about
economics, about geopolitics, about
history, about science, what?
Each of these domains is different.
If you're talking about just general
current affairs, news, all that,
I would say
you should get news from a 360 degree
perspective.
You should get news from the major
established news outlets, BBC, CNN,
um CCTV,
uh Deutsche Welle, Japan, whatever they
have, India, whatever we have here,
which is all going to be parroting the
Western perspective. Get your news from
a 360 degree perspective, from India,
from Russia, from China, from England,
from Germany, from Japan, from the US.
Then get news from various
social media handles.
Then you can use
news scraping algorithms and all. So,
what you have to do is to get a 360
degree perspective.
And then once you have all this
information on a daily basis,
you have to use your own wisdom and
experience and judgment to really
understand what what what the truth is
because it's all going to be propaganda
from a 360 degree perspective. Social
media is going to be propaganda. BBC,
CNN, New York Times, Times of India,
the Chinese thing, Nikkei, everything's
going to have some element of
propaganda.
So,
you've got to
use your own judgment and wisdom at the
end.
AKS Bagga says, "Oleg D Telegram post."
I don't know why YouTube is telling me
to edit.
Oleg D.
Telegram. I don't have Telegram here,
sir. I won't be able to open Telegram.
I won't be able to open Telegram here.
Telegram is something you have on cell
phones. I don't have
I suppose it may be you may be able to
open in browsers, but I'm not opening a
Telegram
channel here.
So, who is Oleg D? Let me find out who
is Oleg D, okay?
Oleg D, Oleg D.
Oleg Deripaska. Okay.
Does he have a Telegram? Deri-
uh Telegram. Does he have Telegram?
Oh, he has Telegram.
Okay, I won't be opening this here
because Telegram
is well, you may have stuff that you
don't want to see here.
Okay.
AKS Bagga says, "How many How many
hours?" It's been what?
3 hours 11 minutes.
Okay, I will request everybody to please
stop taking super chats now. I will
finish the ones that we have now because
it's been 3 hours plus. I should end
this at a reasonable time.
Okay, AKS Bagga says, "Is the US in a
second gilded age as nine out of 10
richest people in the world are from the
US? Can Russia ever be as strong as the
Soviet Union?"
The US is Is it a gilded age? I don't
know what you want to call it. You had
the gilded age in the early 20th
century, right?
Where you had tremendous prosperity and
so on.
If nine of the 10 richest people in the
world are from the US, the US is
obviously the wealthiest country in the
world.
But is everybody wealthy in the US? You
also have poverty in the US. You have
tremendous inequality in the US. There
are a large number of people who have to
work three jobs to put food on the
table.
You know, I'm not sure if it's a gilded
age, but yeah, there are
there's
tremendous wealth in the US, the
wealthiest country in the world for
sure.
Can Russia ever be as strong as the
Soviet Union? It can.
If it gets things right.
It may take time.
And it may not be easy, but it can. It
can be as strong as the Soviet Union,
possibly.
Fields strongman says, "Someone had to
play world police at least until 1990s
and the US did it. World order plus
prevent World War III. But after that,
they should have simply mind their
business, right? No.
Why will somebody simply mind their
business?
If they have all the power in the world,
if they are the greatest power,
why will they mind their business?
You know,
the world doesn't operate on the basis
of morality.
This is how things ought to be. No.
Power has a set of rules of its own.
The US will not mind its own business.
If India were the most powerful nation
in the world today, will it mind its own
business?
It won't.
Let's say you have a zoo.
Open zoo, only one cage, gigantic cage.
And you have a rabbit, you have a fox,
you have a wolf, you have five deer,
you have an elephant, you have a tiger.
You think a tiger will mind his own
business?
He simply can't. He's just too powerful.
He's going to tell everybody how to
live.
He's going to eat half of them whenever
he feels like. That's how it goes.
Surya Bhavan says,
"How did Russian people in other parts
of the world
support communism when it wanted to ban
religion? Most people are Christians.
Didn't Vatican protest?" Well, Vatican
by the time the communist revolutions
happened, the Vatican had lost much of
its power.
The Vatican was all powerful in Europe
for more than a thousand years.
It was the maker and breaker of kings.
Okay, the Vatican was so powerful. But
by the time you have the 20th century
roll into being,
the Vatican was no longer that powerful.
If you protest, who cares?
If someone protests, who cares? The only
thing people care about is what you can
do or can't do.
If all you can do is protest verbally
without taking any
real world action, no one cares.
Yeah. So, how did communism happen?
Because communism was portrayed as a
great thing and people believed it. And
for communist
revolutions to succeed, you need
charismatic leaders. And you had
charismatic leaders who did this. And
maybe some of it was engineered. You
need a lot of money also. So, maybe
there are things that happened behind
the scenes somehow.
Um
Yeah, and see, you're talking about
Europe,
where you had Christianity, which was
the predominant religion. Christianity,
you think it was a great religion?
It was a very oppressive religion.
It was a very controlling religion.
Why is Christianity almost
you know, irrelevant now in the West?
Except for some pockets in the US and so
on. Why has Europe given up on
Christianity?
Because Christianity was very
oppressive.
It burned millions of women alive.
Today your scholars and academicians
will say it was maybe 10, 20,000 women.
It was actually millions.
They're lying.
Christianity was very oppressive.
It was very controlling.
So, when there was a movement to ban all
religion and all, people were very happy
about it. See, this is how there are
multiple factors why these things
succeeded.
Naveen says, "Saddam's claim." Okay, um
Okay, sir. Thank you very much for the
information. All right.
Opposite.
Are you saying the Americans released
Saddam Hussein's genetic profile?
Let me just take a look. Oops, what what
happened here? One second. Give me a
second.
Uh let us
get try and get to the bottom of this
matter.
Um
Saddam Hussein
DNA
results.
Um
Okay, that's all fine. DNA
identification
claims, context, significance.
Saddam Hussein
fast track DNA tests confirm Saddam's
identity.
Indian origin DNA tests. But have the
DNA results been
publicly dis-
results
public
publication.
His full genetic profile has never been
released to the public. Do you read
this, Naveen?
This is the point I've been making.
Saddam Hussein's full genetic profile
has never been released to the public.
It has never been released to the
public. It has never been released to
courts.
YouTube, okay.
Okay, thank you.
Pratik Shenoy says, "Democracy failing
India.
Low IQ, caste obsessed, illiterate
people vote for criminally incompetent
people cause for caste and freebies and
this keeps repeating every 5 years."
We have to
abolish caste.
This four-pronged caste system that has
been imposed upon us
and made part of our system
starting from the British occupation
period. And now your birth certificate,
your school certificates, etc.
Everything has caste.
And you vote on the basis of caste. This
is a huge problem for India.
The government of India must abolish
caste.
Remove all mentions of caste
from all official documents.
Whether it is birth certificate, death
certificate, leaving certificate
marriage certificate, school leaving
certificate, whatever. Remove any
mention of caste.
If you want to give your goddamn
reservations, give them on the basis of
a family's financial status.
That's it.
Then this entire caste obsession will go
away. But politicians will never do
this, right?
So why and why are politicians Why will
politicians politicians never do it?
Because they get votes through these
things.
And what is the root cause of all this?
The so-called system of democracy that
we have.
Why are Indians low IQ?
Because the education system brainwashes
them into remaining into being low IQ.
Your IQ depends on nature plus nurture.
Nurture is your education system.
If the education system
is is is
has specific characteristics, you're
going to end up with low IQ people.
And so on. So the entire system in India
is rigged towards keeping India super
mediocre.
And a key component of this is what we
call the so-called democracy.
Yeah, so all these issues.
Ronit Sahul says, "I am 26. I have
achieved nothing in life, big or small."
All right.
Most people at the age of 26 have not
achieved nothing significant in life.
So it doesn't mean that you should feel
terrible and so on.
You're just 26. You're just starting
off. You have 74 more years, I would
say.
Plenty of time. So get going.
Get your act together. Decide what you
want to achieve in life.
Write down your goals for the next 10
years. What do you Where do you want to
be in 10 years' time?
And then start working on that. And make
the goals big so that when you achieve
even 1/10 of it, you'll feel like you
achieved something. Big or small,
something at least.
Start working on that. Start working on
your skills. Start work working on the
areas where you need to get better. All
right, so Ronit. It doesn't matter. 26
is just starting off.
Don't compare yourself with others.
Don't do that. You may have people you
you know you know your peers, some of
them may have got a good job somewhere
or something. It's not a big
achievement. It's good. I'm not saying
it's not good.
My point is don't compare yourself with
others.
Decide what you want to do in life and
get working on it. All right, Ronit. All
the best. Be positive. And work hard and
work smart.
Rajat says, "When sun turns red giant,
outer solar system planets will have
life?"
Can't say.
Can't say. When the sun becomes a red
giant
it will eventually engulf the Earth.
It's going to expand expand expand. Its
outer layers will expand and it will
engulf the Earth itself. The Earth will
become part of the sun. It'll go inside
the sun.
So
the Earth will essentially
be vaporized.
Uh Mars will be extremely hot.
Jupiter will become a hot hottest
Jupiter.
Um
the biochemistry on on Titan will change
on Enceladus, Europa, etc. They will
change. Um maybe they will have liquid
oceans instead of subsurface oceans. Uh
so maybe some of these moons may have
life.
What about Uranus, Neptune Neptune?
Uh do we have a subsurface ocean on
Triton? Let me see.
Uh Triton.
Triton, do we have a subsurface ocean?
Uh sub
surface ocean. Do we have a subsurface
ocean on Triton?
Yeah, it it does. It likely possesses a
global subsurface ocean of liquid water.
That's Neptune's largest moon. So will
it become liquid? I'm not sure. So you
know, depending on various conditions
and all, you may possibly have some form
of life in the outer planets or in maybe
on some of the moons.
Okay.
Tech test says, "Punjabis fill Pakistan,
but why do many famous Pakistanis have
Iranian ancestry, Benazir Bhutto, Mom
Muhammad Ali Sekhri, Hassan Jahangir,
Nahid Raza born in Iran?"
I don't know.
Iran is a neighboring country now for
Pakistan, right? It used to be our
neighboring country. Now Pakistan is in
the way.
And if it's a neighboring country, you
may sometimes marry people from there.
So um
Murtaza Ali Bhutto, right?
He married an Iranian lady. He actually
married two or three ladies. Uh
Benazir's dad, right? He married an
Iranian lady. That's why Benazir has
Iranian Persian ancestry.
Her mom was Shia, Nusrat Bhutto.
And uh and her dad married an a
Bangladeshi lady as well.
So
look, why do many Pakistanis have
Punjabi
Iranian ancestry? Because Iran is a
neighboring country and I suppose you
easier to marry, I suppose.
Animesh Bharati says, "Could you please
share again the name of the math book
series for kids to help them develop
love for maths?
Especially when the math teachers at
school are not doing a good job." Maths
book series for kids.
Maths for kids.
I don't know any maths for kids books.
Even as a kid a kid, I did not read kids
books. I read serious math books.
If you want
to learn math from scratch I will
recommend the Schaum's series books.
Schaum's outlines.
Okay?
You can start with very basic
mathematics.
Uh very basic mathematics, okay? Like
elementary
not PDF, okay?
I will not um
Okay. Review of So you have you can
study very basic mathematics from there.
Elementary mathematics, you know?
Um
What kind of sample do we have? Let's
see. Do they have a table of contents?
Let's see. Let's see. Let's see. Let's
see. Let's see. Show me that. Okay.
Fundamentals of arithmetic arithmetic.
Number. What's a number? Decimal system.
Number line. That's ABCs of mathematics,
you see? Fundamentals of arithmetic and
introduction to calculators. Fractions,
decimals, percents, signed numbers.
Positive and negative
integers numbers. Fundamentals of
algebra. Laws and operations. Equations
and formulas. So this is all very basic
mathematics.
You can start with this book and then
you can build upwards from there. So the
Schaum's series books series of books is
the best I have personally used. You can
you can start off, you know, a
kid who's like 5 years old with this
with this stuff. As long as the kid is
reasonably intelligent. You know, yeah.
So that's what I would say. And you can
use these books for self-study. You
don't need anyone to teach you if you
have these books. As long as you are
reasonably intelligent. You know,
average
average reasonably I don't know what.
Reasonably intelligent.
Ready always ready says, "When China we
regime change?"
When China we regime change in
Bangladesh or Pakistan at 8, 10, 15, or
20 trillion GDP? I have no idea.
When can we? When can we?
When can we regime change? Probably 10.
10.
Give it 10.
Yeah, give it 10.
I would say 10.
10 should be sufficient.
Uh yeah.
Next. Abhirup Sarkar says, "How does one
make real friends as an adult?"
Well, you need to interact with people.
So you need to be in be in situations
where you regularly interact with new
people. Not just the same crowd, but new
people regularly. So in the US, people
go to bars and get drunk and talk to
people and make friends or whatever, you
know?
Um if you want to make friends as an
adult
you don't have to go to bars.
You should be part of
activities, for example, where you get
to meet people regularly. Maybe be part
of a sports club
of some kind.
Or maybe
maybe as part of your job if you get to
travel or something. So yeah, obviously
it's it's harder to make friends as an
adult
maybe start a podcast.
Start a podcast and invite lots of
guests, people you don't know.
So you have to be creative. You have to
find ways of doing it. You have to find
ways of
giving yourself the the maximum possible
chance of meeting new people on a
regular basis. And then sometimes you'll
hit off with somebody and become
friends.
So the
the key
idea is that you have to regularly
you have to meet new people on a regular
basis consistently. Then you can make
real friends. So find creative ways of
being in the situation where you meet
new people regularly and then you'll
make friends.
Vidyamanya says, "What is the US up to
and what will be the impact on the
world?" The US is in the process of
implementing a new version of the Monroe
Doctrine. It is focusing on the Western
Hemisphere first, hemispheric defense
and the hemisphere first, but it's also
focusing on the in that entire world.
It is it is now saying that no
extraterritorial power will be allowed
to interfere in the Western Hemisphere.
And even regional actors will not be
allowed to go against the US. The US
will be the super cop in the region. So,
it has now changed the situation in
Venezuela. Essentially, for a long time
it will remain the way it is. It now
owns the oil of Venezuela. It also owns
the gold of Venezuela.
And now it's going to focus on other
parts of the world, maybe
maybe Somaliland, maybe Yemen, maybe
Iran,
and so on. So, the impact of the world
it's it's going to be pretty
destabilizing.
King Ritwik says, is James A Kanglu from
Superpower Bangladesh? Well, I I I think
James is from the fantastic country of
Great Britain,
England.
Uh Biju Saikia says, "Abrahamic
religions have always prohibited
atheism, but Dharmic religions have
never probably prohibited it. Maybe
that's why most atheists Hindus don't
really hate Hinduism. Why our religions
gave freedom to the to be atheists?"
Why did our religion give certain kind
of freedom?
Because being free
to explore various options is part of
our culture. It's part of our religion.
Questioning is part of our religion.
Inquiry
is part of our religion. Read the
Nasadiya Sukta,
which is the creation hymn
of the Rigveda, the oldest religious
text in the world.
Would you like to see what the Nasadiya
Sukta says?
Nasadiya
Sukta. Okay, let's go to what Wikipedia
has to say about it.
Okay?
It's called the hymn of creation.
There was neither nonexistence nor
existence then.
Neither the realm of space nor the sky
which is beyond. What stirred? Where did
it stir? In whose protection? There was
neither death nor immortality then. No
distinguishing sign of night or day.
That one breathed
windless by its own impulse. Other than
that, there was nothing beyond. Darkness
there was at first, but darkness hidden.
Without distinctive marks, this all was
water.
That which becoming by the void was
covered, that one by force of heat came
into being. Who really knows? Who will
here proclaim it?
From where was it all produced?
From where did this creation come?
The gods came afterwards with the
creation of this universe.
Who then knows from where it has arisen?
Whether gods will created it, whether he
was mute, perhaps it formed itself,
perhaps it did not.
The supreme Brahman of the world, all
pervasive and all knowing,
he indeed he indeed knows,
but perhaps he himself doesn't know,
perhaps no one knows.
This is deeply skeptical.
This is
deeply skeptical. This is deeply
agnostic.
It raises the question of who created
the universe. The gods came came into
existence with the creation of the
universe. Who created them?
Do we know?
Does the creator know?
Perhaps he himself doesn't know, perhaps
we will never know.
That is the core of of what we call
Hinduism.
It is
it is the spirit of inquiry. It is the
spirit of skepticism.
The Rigveda has an element of deep
agnosticism within it.
So, when that's part of your culture,
obviously you don't need to give freedom
to be atheist or whatever. You can be
what you want.
Abhirup Sarkar says, "How does one come
out of trust issues as a as an adult?" I
I don't know.
I I have no idea.
I don't even know what trust issues are.
Means you are unable to trust people.
Um
Look, I don't know about this.
This is something that's like beyond
my my my my my skill set or my
realm of knowledge.
Trust issues and all. Maybe you should
consult a
a specialist, a professional about this.
I I have no idea. Sorry. Uh it's it's
not part of my experience, you know,
trust issues or whatever.
So, can't say. Very sorry. All the best.
Please please consult somebody
who actually is a professional in this.
Then you may be able to get the answers,
sir.
Kiki Sushant, thank you very much, Kiki
Sushant G. I really appreciate it.
Thank you, sir.
Achintya Anand says,
"Mount Mandar and oldest temple is in
Bihar."
Okay.
What is Mount Mandar? I've never heard
of it.
Mount
What is Mount Mandar?
Mandar
Okay.
The mountain that is
the churning rod used in Samudra
manthan.
I see. I see. And the oldest Okay. Okay.
Thank you for this piece of information.
Very interesting. I'll look into it
later.
Okay. Sam the Gamer says, "Medicine
wishes
go well. Got a fever. Need blessings."
Get well, sir.
You got a fever? Well, take care of your
health. Get some rest. Take the
medicines that you need to take.
And get well at the earliest. All the
best. Do well and get well soon.
Look forward to looking forward to
seeing you seeing you in the future.
Okay? All the best.
Ankur Sarraf
Thank you very much, Ankur Sarraf G.
Cash Flow Circus says, "Your thoughts on
the Jewish Lev Tahor clan and its
controversies?"
People who have escaped the clan have
spoken about their unscrupulous
activities. I have never heard of the
Lev Tahor clan until today.
So, I have no thoughts about it. I I
don't know what it is. What is a Lev
Tahor clan? Let's Let's quickly Google
this.
Lev Tahor
clan
Lev Tahor clan Ultra-Orthodox Jewish
cult founded in Israel by
Helbrans in 1988.
And so on. Okay, I am not aware of this.
I don't I'm This is the first time I'm
hearing of it, so
I don't have any thoughts about it at at
this point in time.
I'll look into it.
King Ritwik says, "Do you think Kim Il
Sung did the right thing by closing off
North Korea because then only USA cannot
do regime change?"
These are the problem of democracy.
Well, right thing wrong thing
There's no right or wrong.
There are different ways.
Each ways has some trade-off.
In some things you are exposed to more
risk,
but you get more benefits too,
potentially. In other ways you are
exposed to less risk, but then you're
closed off.
So, I don't know what's right, what's
wrong. Is it good for the people of
North Korea?
Maybe maybe not.
We are told, especially the Western
media says that the people of North
Korea are very badly repressed. There is
famine, whatnot.
Is it true? Is it not? I have no idea.
But being closed off, being isolated
from the world, insulated, it's it's not
a good thing.
Because I know that in the 1980s
until the 1980s India was like that.
When I was a little kid,
India was closed off from the rest of
the world.
There was one TV channel that
broadcasted in the evening for 2-3
hours.
They showed news twice, once in Hindi,
once in English.
On Doordarshan.
And the news was what?
So-and-so minister said so-and-so thing
today.
So-and-so minister cut the ribbon for
so-and-so inauguration today.
They It's all about what minister said.
You never got to know what was happening
outside of the outside of the country.
So, India was actually like North Korea.
You may not believe it today. India has
changed so much.
That's how our leaders kept this
country. Do you think it's a good thing
to be completely isolated like that?
Insulated from the rest of the world.
Terrible.
Uh but yeah, if you become an open
country, obviously there is more chance
of regime change and all, but
there are ways of preventing that also.
Uh so, you can be a noninsular nation
without having to be democratic.
I mean, look at the Gulf nations. Do you
see any democracy there?
But they are not closed off.
There are various ways of doing things.
Vamsi B says, "You If US hegemony were
to diminish,
how due to what it would happen?"
If other nations become more powerful,
like way more powerful,
then US hegemony could
diminish. So, for that, nations like
China, Russia, India would need to be
more powerful. Or maybe one of these
nations would have to be way more
powerful. So, relatively the US strength
will then diminish, and then US hegemony
will also diminish.
Shreya Srivastava says, "To keep our
Dharmic civilization alive, what should
we do?
Which key organization to support with
money or time?
I see youth is influenced without any
civilizational awareness."
Look, I will not recommend any
organizations here.
I'm not in the I'm not doing that.
But how can individuals keep the Dharmic
civilization alive?
By practicing Dharmic practices.
By continuing the traditions of your
ancestors.
Don't let those traditions die.
Don't let the culture die.
Visit your local temples. You don't have
to go to a big temple where there's a
big queue every day.
Visit your local temples. Support the
local
uh religious activities. Teach your kids
uh the Ramayana, the Mahabharata, the
Bhagavad Gita.
Right? Whatever uh
specific practices your family lineages
has
been conducting practicing keep those
alive.
Meet like-minded people. There's so much
you can do,
right? I will not talk about which
organization to support with money or
time.
Support your local temple with some
money.
Give a 100 rupees a month.
That's better than zero rupees a month.
If you can give more, great.
Make sure the temple funds are the
temple funds are not stolen by the
government. If that that's the kind of
temple it is then better not to give
money in the hundie. Maybe give it in
the priest's pocket or whatever. So,
there are various ways of doing it.
If you are a wealthy person, build new
temples.
There's plenty that can be done without
giving money to some organization. And
if there is some organization that you
are,
you know, fond of, you can certainly
support that organization with money or
time.
My point is I will not here publicly say
support this or that organization
because
100 haters will crop up then that why
didn't you support my organization my
favorite favored organization. So, I'm
not going to do that here.
King Ritvik says,
"I have a dream to visit all the great
temples of our country. I'm from Odisha,
so I regularly visit visit Puri
Jagannath. Suggest me all the great
temples."
Well,
Puri Jagannath Jagannath Puri, right?
So, that is a Vaishnava temple,
obviously.
Look, there are so many great temples
across the country. There are Vaishnava
temples, there are Shaiva temples, there
are Shakti temples.
There's a whole list of Jyotirlingas,
right? The Jyotirlingas which are
Shaivite temples. There are many great
um
um Vaishnava temples in the country.
Um I cannot I don't remember all the
great temples. Look, there is
uh
there's obviously
ask me I'll say Somnath, right? The the
great temple of Somnath.
Um the great Ram Mandir, obviously.
Um
I won't be able to tell you all the
temples. You just do a Google search,
right? You'll you'll find all the all
the
the major temples in India. Tirupati,
um Sri Padmanabhaswamy Temple. There are
so many temples.
So, many of the great temples that we
have still standing today are in the
south,
southern part of India.
Uh so, you can
make a list of the great temples in
southern India. You can make a list of
the great Jyotirlingas. One or two of
these are in Pakistan today, you know,
Hinglaj Mata, etc. But, you know, Shakti
Peethas and so on.
So, yeah, make do a Google search you'll
get all the all the temples.
Fast Nail says, "Should countries move
away from oil dependence dependency in
the long run?"
Well, sure, but what do you move
towards? If you want to let's say you
want to move towards nuclear energy.
But, you can't have a nuclear reactor in
a motorcycle, right? Or in or in a
four-wheeler. You can't.
So, we'll need or or or let's say you
move towards solar.
But, can solar power reliably
uh
power two-wheelers and four-wheelers and
so on? So, we're going to have to
eventually find a better source of
energy.
But, right now
right now we are dependent on oil.
Ideally, we should all move away from
oil dependency so that we don't pollute
the environment so much and all.
But, we're going to have to make
technological breakthroughs for that to
happen. But, yes, ideally this should
happen. No question.
Vinay says, "Should I build a life in
the US after my undergraduate degree in
medical engineering as I like it here
despite the challenges? Is it selfish?"
It's not selfish.
And if it is selfish, so what?
So, what?
Why should you not be selfish?
I think I would say do whatever is best
for yourself. If you are a young person,
be selfish. It is important for young
people to be selfish at least until the
age of 40.
Focus on yourself.
Focus on your career. Focus on earning
wealth.
Focus on acquiring skills. Focus on
acquiring positive beneficial
experiences.
Focus on yourself at least until the age
of 40. Be completely selfish until the
age of 40.
Then at the age of 40 or 45, reconsider.
Think about it. Have I experienced
enough? Have I enjoyed life enough? Do I
have enough wealth? Do I now maybe want
to serve my nation, my civilization? If
at the age of 40, 45 you decide that now
it's the time,
then you can think of reinvesting some
of the money back in India.
At the age of 20, 25 you have no money
first of all.
So, how will you serve India even if you
want to? You can't you can't serve
society without money.
So, I would say
do whatever is best for yourself.
Be selfish at least until the age of 40.
Okay, Vinay. All the best.
Raj says, "Studying is vital for exams,
yet I deviate after two hours. Why does
the brain resist focus and how can
students rebuild attention
scientifically?"
Your brain resists focus because
studying is extremely boring.
Your brain resists focus because the
education system is mediocre and there
there are there are better ways of
studying and better curriculums.
So, what can you do about this? How can
you retain
attention and so on?
Well,
there is something called inter interval
training
in in physical in in exercise.
In interval training, it's it's a form
of cardio.
So, you sprint for 30 seconds.
Sprint like
at the highest intensity for 30 seconds.
Then you walk
at a very moderate pace for like three
minutes.
Then you once again sprint very
intensely
at the highest intensity for 30 seconds.
Then you walk moderate pace for three
minutes or you can switch switch up, you
know, maybe maybe 20 seconds, four
minutes, 30 seconds, two minutes,
whatever.
But, that's what you do. So,
if your brain resists focus, do do your
studying in in in sprints.
Study for 20 minutes, then take a
five-minute break.
Just walk around or do some push-ups or
do some squats.
Do something that is completely
non-mental
for five minutes. Then come back, study
for 20 minutes, then again take a
five-minute break. And do that
do that periodization for let's say two
hours, three hours, whatever.
Then take a one-hour break
or two-hour break. Go watch a movie. Do
something. Then return and do another
three hours stint like this. That's all.
So, you have to be creative in this.
Yeah?
You do shock the brain into different
patterns.
Try something creative like that, right?
All the best.
Ankita ji says, "Some experts say
colonization has always been there,
never gone really. After actual
colonization, there is neo-colonization.
Petrodollar control next is
legitimization of digital currency,
possibly stable coins and so on. What's
my opinion?" Oh, absolutely.
Colonization has never disappeared.
There is neo-colonization. Take the
example of Africa.
After the first and second world wars
around that period,
the western nations supposedly moved
away from moved out from Africa.
There is this famous Italian movie in
the movie called Africa Addio.
It's pretty hard to watch at times
because of the scenes and all, but I
will recommend it to those who are
interested. Africa
Africa Addio. So, this was from
1966.
And Africa Addio means goodbye Africa,
which means the Europeans are leaving
Africa.
So, the message that's being sent
indirectly to the world is that we left
Africa by the 1960s. We left Africa
alone and Africa African countries
became independent. And if Africa is in
a mess today, it's it is their fault.
It's not our fault.
But, the truth is that the European
powers left Africa physically. Boots
boots were taken off the ground, but
they continued controlling Africa
indirectly by
by funding dictators. By cultivating
dictatorships in all the countries they
had left.
So, they became
patrons of the dictators who became
clients.
And they would give the dictators
whatever they wanted, money, etc. And
the dictators would allow the Europeans
to indirectly plunder the countries. So,
that's neo-colonization of Africa.
When it comes to other countries like
Japan and so on, these are still
occupied by the West. So, there there is
still colonization.
Then there is vassalhood, which is
indirect colonization and so on. Then
there is the petrodollar situation which
which allows the US to control the
entire world's economy.
They also control Swift, by which they
control countries. If you if they cut
you off from Swift, you are cut off from
the rest of the world.
And then you will have digital currency.
So, colonization has always been there.
You're absolutely right.
You're absolutely right, Ankita ji.
Colonization has never gone.
The world is still run
through an imperial system.
It's just called the rules-based world
order or whatever it is.
But, it's at the end of the day we are
ruled by an empire, which is the
American empire, which is nothing but a
reincarnation or a continuation of the
British empire.
But, today we are told that it's a
democratic world, free and fair world,
and so on, which is an illusion. So, you
are absolutely right.
EKS Bagga says,
"Are your geopolitical sources from
France?"
Which geopolitical sources from France?
Um I'm not sure which sources I have
from France.
Do I have sources from France?
What's a geopolitical source? You mean
source of news or source of something
else?
I'm not sure what you're asking, sir.
Could you please be more clear?
I'm I'm really not sure.
I don't have any sources
in France as such.
Uh,
probably the answer is no, but I'm not
very clear about what you're asking.
Akesh Bagga says, "Should India have
special economic zones like China?"
That's a great idea.
That's a great idea. The government
should consider this. We have something
called GIFT City
in Gujarat somewhere, right?
That's a special economic zone.
Hong Kong used to be a special economic
zone of China.
Why can't India have such zones?
Where you have a different set of rules,
where you have zero red tape, where you
have maybe a laissez-faire economy.
That's a great idea, actually. We should
have these in every state
to kickstart, jumpstart the economy
in various parts of India.
That's a great idea. I don't know why
these things are not implemented. I just
don't get it.
Kri-
Krishnant Bordoloi says, "You think
someday one day the US will come after
India properly?"
Maybe.
Maybe not.
Maybe, maybe not.
Depending on how India behaves, on how
India plays the game.
Unknown says, "PC with Sanjeev Sanyal,
Ruchir Sharma, Surya Kane." PC, podcast.
Are you recommending podcasts?
Good recommendations. Thank you.
Ravi Mohan says, "Islamic Moroccan
architecture of Spain is seen as one of
the influential medieval styles by
architects like Rafael Moneo and Juhani
Pallasmaa, Finnish.
Yet many in the West show little
interest in studying our ancient Indian
architecture."
See,
India is seen as
a culture that was defeated.
And India is resurgent today. And they
hate it.
So, there is this very strong sense of
Hinduphobia, etc. in India across the
world.
And there is this this this this
campaign across the world to deny the
Indian origins of everything, of
anything,
and to just erase India out of any
discussion.
Right?
So,
and Indians themselves are are like
brown coolies,
brown sepoys. Brown apparently is
a racist term.
That's what Vir Das once claimed.
Anyway, forget about Vir Das. Uh, so,
Indians themselves
try to
play down the importance of India.
So, my point is who cares what the West
does? Why don't our academics, our
researchers
start studying Indian architectural
styles and writing books about them,
writing research papers about them? Our
own goddamned economics are not
uh,
academicians, academics are not
interested at all in these things.
We have to start with ourselves, from
our universities. Look at the kind of
rotten research that comes out of our
universities, so-called research.
Our own researchers have zero interest.
They're all left loonies.
Our our our humanities departments are
leftist snake pits.
That's the problem.
So, when your country, when India itself
doesn't produce any any research about
Indian architecture, Indian history,
Indian architectural styles, and so on,
why will the rest of the world bother?
That's the problem. Let's not blame the
rest of the world.
Our own academics are a serious problem.
Why do we
keep paying them from our taxpayer money
when they are doing nothing to to take
our nation's interest forward? I don't
get it. Why is the government of India
still funding these third-rate people?
Why aren't we reforming the education
system?
All right.
Mahendra Mahendra Singh Jadon says, "Can
you suggest a broad road map sources to
educate myself about history and
geopolitics
without being overwhelmed by it? I have
a growing curiosity for it." Well, when
you say history, what are you talking
about? Are you talking about Indian
history? Are you talking about world
history? What are you talking about,
sir?
If you're talking about world history,
well, that's a massive topic.
I am still learning world history.
Somebody yesterday asked me about the
Marshall Plan. I could not remember what
the Marshall Plan was all about, the
details, the specifics.
You see,
of course I've studied read the Marshall
Plan, read about it,
but I could not recall the specifics at
the time.
So,
history, world history is a vast topic.
Different regions of the world,
different eras, time periods.
If you want to study See, you can't
understand geopolitics without
understanding history.
And to understand geopolitics, you have
to understand world history. How will
you understand world history? You have
to start from broad strokes,
and then dive down into more specific
details.
Uh, broad road map.
The broad road map is first acquaint
yourself with world history,
high-level world history.
Uh, study about Europe,
study about India, about China, about
Persia,
um, Greece,
essentially the Americas, all of it
essentially.
Get a decent
but not detailed, not deep
broad understanding of world history.
That will
hopefully give you some information.
Then you can start div- diving diving
deep into specific
parts of world history that you find
more interesting, and so on. It takes
time. You see,
it will take you at least a decade.
I will not lie to you and say that you
can get an understanding in 6 months.
I started studying history, reading
history out of my own curiosity when I
was like 7 or 8 years old, 8 8 9 years
old.
Yeah.
It's been a long time. I'm still
learning.
So,
if you want one recommendation, read The
History of Civilization by Will Durant.
Let me show this on the screen.
History of Civilization.
The Story of Civilization
by Will and Ariel Durant. 11-volume set
of books.
It will take you maybe 2 3 years to read
this. You read that, you get a solid
foundation. All right, sir. All the
best. Ankur Sarraf Credit of Indian
nukes,
Atal Ji or Indira Ji?
Look, Indira Ji, under her leadership,
we tested a nuclear weapon in 1974.
Then what did we do? We went to sleep.
If we tested a weapon in 1974, why
didn't we become a nuclear power?
Because Indira Ji said that we have only
done this for demonstration purposes.
Okay. Now we will
put it on the shelf and forget about it.
Atal Ji
tested five nukes
and then operationalized the nuclear
deterrent. Who should we give credit to?
Please tell me. I would give it to Atal
Ji.
Uh,
Anshu Jain says, "How much realistic
chance is there of China attacking and
conquering Taiwan in 2027?"
50/50.
Maybe 50/50.
Anirudh says, "Should India wage war and
defeat a bigger nation like how Japan
defeated Russia to cement respect for
itself among the world order?" I don't
give a damn what respect.
Let the whole world disrespect my
country. I don't care.
I care about my country's power.
Let them dislike me,
but they should be scared of me.
So, I Why should you fight a war to gain
respect?
You fight a war for very specific,
concrete political
and military objectives. You don't fight
a war for respect.
Okay?
And today we
The next 20 years, I don't want any war.
I want uh, economic growth. So, I really
we should not do any of that. Okay? We
have to be realistic.
Okay.
Rush God says, "How would Chanakya free
temples?"
Chanakya would rule the country and he
would write the laws that temples should
be free.
That's what he would do. He would first
take power.
He would first grab power.
If you want to free temples, you have to
have power, which means you have to
first take power.
Then you write the laws.
That's how you free temples. That's how
Chanakya would do it.
And that brings me finally to the end of
today's live stream.
Okay.
3 hours 57 minutes.
That's a long long long long live
stream.
Okay, people. I'm going to end it over
here. It is what time? It's almost 12:00
p.m. here in India. So, thank you so
much, everybody. It was real fun. A lot
of questions, wide variety of questions.
Enjoyed taking them all. Thank you very
much, everyone. I will see you in next
week's live streams. We're going to
continue this wonderful
interaction that we have. Look forward
to seeing you next week's live streams.
Keep learning. Keep raising your
standards. Keep asking questions. I'll
see you very soon in the next one. Take
care. Bye-bye.